<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on Haojin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on Haojin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>@2018-2023 Haojin Li</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 22:08:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zion National Park</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-03-11-zion-national-park.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 22:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-03-11-zion-national-park.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;转眼间已经20岁了。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One third passed</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-02-21-one-third-passed.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-02-21-one-third-passed.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This semester has been surprisingly long, in a positive sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto, Niagara Falls, and Cancun!</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-01-08-from-toronto-to-cancun.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 14:32:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-01-08-from-toronto-to-cancun.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well yes I flew all the way from the far north to the far south&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto-Montreal-Ottawa Road Trip</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-12-27-toronto-montreal-ottawa.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-12-27-toronto-montreal-ottawa.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So here I am in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My sophomore Fall</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-12-20-my-sophomore-fall.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-12-20-my-sophomore-fall.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a bittersweet semester with so many things happening out of control in an unexpected way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shenandoah National Park</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-11-25-shenandoah-national-park.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-11-25-shenandoah-national-park.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was my first ever self-planed hiking roadtrip which turned out to be amazing ever since the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer done!</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-08-28-summer-done.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 22:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-08-28-summer-done.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wooooo summer can&amp;rsquo;t be better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Madness?</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-04-09-march-madness.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 22:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-04-09-march-madness.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy March that has nothing to do with March Madness, but crazier than March Madness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Unwrap</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-03-05-spring-semester-unwrap.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 22:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-03-05-spring-semester-unwrap.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We just lost the most important home game today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021年终总结</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 23:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;很多人称这一年为被偷走的一年，于我而言，却意义非凡。是重大的转折，又仿佛是日出时分，朝霞最亮，最广阔，拥有能够扩展整个天空的野心的时刻。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC - Day4</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-20-washington-dc-day4.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 20:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-20-washington-dc-day4.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天算是比较chill的一天，唯一的行程就是National Zoo。说来惭愧，作为一个中国人第一次看到大熊猫居然是在美国首都。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC - Day3</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-19-washington-dc-day3.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-19-washington-dc-day3.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天的行程比较松散，中午才从住处出发。主要徒步浏览了Georgetown还有Georgetown大学。当然，还有最爱的胡辣汤。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC - Day2</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-18-washington-dc-day2.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 23:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-18-washington-dc-day2.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天混迹于各个博物馆之间，算是把美国的历史全方位各角度体验了一番，颇有收获。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC - Day1</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-17-washington-dc-day1.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 22:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-17-washington-dc-day1.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;寒假了，大家又都各奔东西。美国的假期确实好多，让我不知如何是好。漫长的寒假还是决定出去走一走，尽管一个月前刚从纽约回来。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York City - Day5</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-29-new-york-city-day5.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 21:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-29-new-york-city-day5.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;最最最后一天了，现在正坐在从纽约飞往durham的飞机上，刚刚飞过繁华的曼哈顿上空，我甚至能够清楚地看到布鲁克林大桥、自由女神像。是时候做个总结了。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York City - Day4</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-28-new-york-city-day4.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 23:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-28-new-york-city-day4.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天算是在纽约最后完整的一天了，明晚就要坐飞机离开了。今天也是感恩节假期的最后一天，这个我从两周前就开始期待的假期，无以言说的圆满。从序幕到进行时到临近尾声，我感恩遇到的一切新朋友，老朋友，遇见的新事物，旧事物。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York City - Day3</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-27-new-york-city-day3.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 23:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-27-new-york-city-day3.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;出人意料，这是我第一次觉得旅游的时光过的好慢，每天都游历了无数，结识了无数，感悟了无数。今天是第三天，也是想对来说较平淡的一天，却也是有额外的小确幸。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York City - Day2</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-26-new-york-city-day2.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 11:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-26-new-york-city-day2.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;真的太开心了，感觉不可能比今天更开心了。现在应该是喝醉了，想着喝醉了写一篇博客也很特别的，于是在凌晨两点决定也写博客。我也不知道自己会说什么胡话。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York City - Day1</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-25-new-york-city-day1.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 22:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-25-new-york-city-day1.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;终于来到了心心念念的纽约，也算是一场说走就走的旅行了。尽管机票两周前早早地就订好了，但行李是在走的当天收拾的，也没有任何旅行计划，就想着一股脑先挤进这座世界城。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It has been a long long time</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-10-23-it-has-been-a-long-long-time.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 02:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-10-23-it-has-been-a-long-long-time.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;哇，确实很久没有写博客了。半年真的只是弹指一挥间。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;也许连我自己也预料不到，已然在地球的另一端了。新的国度，新的生活，新的学校，新的一切，我充满激动。虽说如今也过去了两个多月，我始终内心有一种无法抑制的好奇与激动驱使。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我想先说回以前。这个暑假，绝不是最难忘的暑假，也绝非最乏味的一个暑假，直到现在内心仍然充满着复杂的情感，我想去用浅薄的语言去描述，却做不到。这个暑假，像是做了一切应该在这个暑假做的事情，去看望了小学初中高中老师，去真正跟朋友们玩遍了整个西安，去见到了想见到的所有人，画上了所有该画上完美句号。令我最意外的竟是学会了开车。不在于拿驾照的难度，只是单纯享受驾驶的乐趣。我总是感叹于时间飞逝，自己还未有一个成年人的心智、决策、经历却已然成为了成年人。唯独学会开车，真真实实地证明了我拥有了一项成年人该拥有的技能。坐在车里，系好安全带，手握方向盘，总感觉自己成熟了几分。能够驱车和朋友们去山里农家乐，也是让我感到最开心的一件事。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Spring Festival with Family</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-02-27-last-spring-festival-with-family.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 23:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-02-27-last-spring-festival-with-family.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year of OX, the last Spring Festival I could spend time with family members together. In my childhood memory, the New Year was full of happiness, mostly sounds of firecrackers&amp;hellip; However, as growing up I find less and less interest and meaningful this traditional festival is. It soon became a period of blank. Nothing much I could do. Yet, this year, is completely different for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom was the first person reminded me of the importance of this year. She planned a lot of places to go where we never had available time to visit together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Robot Contest Finals</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-12-08-world-robot-contest-finals.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 23:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-12-08-world-robot-contest-finals.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was revised on March 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-short-break-during-the-application-season&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;A short break during the application season &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it comes, the application seasion, full of tension, sadness and happiness. At this time, just after finsihing submitting all UC applications, I decided to join this competiton held in Foshan, Guangdong, which is a prosperous city around the Guangzhou. It is a short break for me, for I have some time to reflect the early application season including EA and UC and better think how could I improve in the future. Also, I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken any VEX competition for almost a year due to the COVID. It is the best time for me to catch up with this brand new season and implement my new-learned knowledge in real match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;mx-auto my-0 rounded-md&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/HaojinMacBookPro/image-20210305234436333.png&#34; alt=&#34;image-20210305234436333&#34; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short trip to Beijing</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-10-31-a-short-trip-to-beijing.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 22:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-10-31-a-short-trip-to-beijing.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month is really a busy month. Writing essays for application, preparing for TOEFL, learning school courses and participating in Yau Science Awards really stressed me a lot. I feel like I have never been busy as much as now. It&amp;rsquo;s not only about my academic works, since I need to consider many other things that are simple but costs tons of time. All things combined,it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge for me and I need to and have to admit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;coming-to-beijing&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Coming to Beijing &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week long prepare with my mentor, reviewing my paper and debugging my neural network model, I came to Beijing for semifinal of Yau Science Award(Computer) yesterday. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve been to many places without my parents, I was accompanied with teachers or schoolmates. This trip is truly the first trip that I went alone. To be honest, I even was a little nervous at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything went OK the first day. Arriving by bullet train, I took 3 subway lines to go to my hotel next to Tsinghua University. The hotel is fine but I booked a room without windows for cheaper price. However, it was really a awful experience that I felt unwell staying at the room. (I swear I would never book a room without room again) So I decided to go to the university for checking the route in advance just in case that I might get lost the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good impression of Beijing based on previous visits. No exception, it&amp;rsquo;s the same this time. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a prejudice or something else. Anyway, I don&amp;rsquo;t like this city. It imposes bad feeling to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Exercises</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-30-physical-exercises.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-30-physical-exercises.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 28th, I went to a military training base in rural area of my city with my fellow students. Originally, I thought it would be a tough time based on all my past formidable experience with such training. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take it anymore during my time in both middle and high school. I took a trip and had computer science classes instead. A fun fact is that I became the whitest among my class after they coming back from training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from worry, excitement also haunted around me because it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time to have a training. The result turned out it didn&amp;rsquo;t let me down and I really learned a lot from this fantastic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-team-leader&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Being a team leader &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying my best to be the team leader is always my style, especially participating in a short-time camp. I frimly deem it&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity to promote and improve myself. Then I became the leader of group 6 without any hesitate. I deeply know that I am lack of leadership and most important, the decisive personality. This time I failed again on improving that. Everytime I become a leader in a program, unfortunately, I never felt improvement in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I believe I did great a great job. Organizing the team, encourging everyone doing high-altitude program and cimmitting myself to everything I can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first VEX tournament of the season</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-07-23-my-first-vex-tournament-of-the-season.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-07-23-my-first-vex-tournament-of-the-season.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I am on the bullet train from Xi’an to Baoding, crossing one tunnel after another, passing one bridge after another. Just a few minutes ago, I was sleeping deeply, but now I think I am conscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sleepless-night&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Sleepless night &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning of the summer vacation, I was studying TOEFL everyday following a regular routine – getting up at 7AM, doing TOEFL practice all the day and then going to bed at 11PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Last night even didn’t close my eyes for a while because of the unfinished autonomous program. It’s a hard and harsh work putting tons of parameters and variables to my mind simultaneously. Fortunately, with my team members Tony and Jessica helping me reset the match field quickly and accurately, finally I got it. Never forget the colorful cubes leaps on the match field which seem to lose control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nervous-time&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Nervous time &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I didn’t put too many efforts in the VEX competition these summer vacation. I just came to participate in training two days before our setting off. I am really awkward to my excellent team member and coach Mr. Han.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robot that will be used in the competition hadn’t been finished two days before. Our manipulator Tony hadn’t practice controlling the robot like catching the cube and pile them up in the specific area which is not easy and definitely needs time to be familiar with the way of controlling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we had done everything in time under the unity of our team which is the most valuable and precious thing I got from the robot club. I saw everyone mounting screw carefully, writing engineer log amazingly… There exists many good personalities and characters that I need to learn from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer vacation starts now</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-07-08-summer-vacation-starts-now.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-07-08-summer-vacation-starts-now.md/</guid>
      <description>A colorful semester has gone A lot of words I want to say… This period of time I studied and lived in International Course Campus really impressed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A perfect event</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-26-a-perfect-event.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-26-a-perfect-event.md/</guid>
      <description>A fantastic and amazing event that I will never forget I was in the front of the lobby hanging our robot with my teammate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The true first day of 2019 VEX Worlds</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-22-the-true-first-day-of-2019-vex-worlds-1.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-22-the-true-first-day-of-2019-vex-worlds-1.md/</guid>
      <description>Fantastic &amp;amp; Unsatisfactory flights The marvellous sun rising in the morning on the flight from Xi&amp;rsquo;an to Beijing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago day trip</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-22-chicago-day-trip.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-22-chicago-day-trip.md/</guid>
      <description>The server&amp;rsquo;s previous technical issues have caused the loss of images and data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming back</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-15-coming-back.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-15-coming-back.md/</guid>
      <description>How is life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIT REFRESH</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-03-10-hit-refresh.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-03-10-hit-refresh.md/</guid>
      <description>It’s my first blog in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>济南Day1 随记</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-01-28-%E6%B5%8E%E5%8D%97day1-%E9%9A%8F%E8%AE%B0.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-01-28-%E6%B5%8E%E5%8D%97day1-%E9%9A%8F%E8%AE%B0.md/</guid>
      <description>The server&amp;rsquo;s previous technical issues have caused the loss of images and data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
