<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Haojin&#39;s Blog</title>
  
  <subtitle>Keep Mindful Living.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/"/>
  <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.haojin.li/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Haojin Li</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>One third passed</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2023/02/21/Reflect-Life-2023-02-21-One-third-passed/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2023/02/21/Reflect-Life-2023-02-21-One-third-passed/</id>
    <published>2023-02-21T05:13:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This semester has been surprisingly long, in a positive sense.</p><span id="more"></span><p>This might be the first time I could sit down and begin typing my blog post during a Monday night. I just finished running 10km on a treadmill and am feeling really good right now to write something down.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202302210058617.png" alt="Volunteering with Duke Forest!"></p><p>The semester has been quite long for me. Last semester passed in a blink of the eye while this semester I have experienced so much. By experiencing, I mean mostly emotionally and things happened in my head. For example, I have more responsibilities. Every week I am thinking about how to make sure APO brothers show up to the weekly service events I coordinated. It has proven that my bugging all the time works very well and a decent number of people showed up every time. The moment where more-than-expected people showed up to my events, I felt a strong sense of achievement and mostly happiness. This has been my source of motivations to fulfil my Service VP responsibilities. Apart from that, I was trying to date a girl which didn’t end up very well but costs tremendous mental energy. However, I finally have been through the experience once. It was great to get to partially to know a girl and get a better understanding of love. The ordeal has provided clarity to me, and even the most unremarkable and implausible romance plots in movies now appear plausible and sensible.</p><h2 id="Classes"><a href="#Classes" class="headerlink" title="Classes"></a>Classes</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202302210101257.png" alt="A diagram to explain concepts in Capital: Critique of Political Economy"></p><p>I very much enjoyed all the classes I am taking, of course except the discrete math class. My favorable class would definitely be Marxism and Society, which I decided to take out of purely curiosity. The professor was extremely good at explaining Marx’s pieces and all the esoteric concepts. To be honest, I didn’t really do the readings but every time he breaks down everything in such an organic and logical way. Mostly importantly, I got a full score on the first midterm! I know it was not a hard core midterm but I at least prove to myself that I am capable of learning something not cs. Reflecting upon the class, I realize I enjoy absorbing all the unique views and ideology proposed by Marx. Whether feasible or not, it is intriguing to get to know his theories. Admittedly, my classmates are way more smarter and insightful than me. Sometimes I could not even understand their speaking in the class. But overall it’s great to simply be with them and be exposed to a distinctive academic environment.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202302210059911.png" alt="Playing Exploding Kittens"></p><p>Similarly, my Intro to Political Philosophy class provides another whole different perspective which ironically Marx refutes about. Reading pieces from Plato, Socrates, Hobbes, Machiavelli was such a fun journey, even though it was painful when composing an academically sound paper to submit. I particularly like Machiavelli’s views and his book The Prince. Most things he stated is so true given the current political dynamics of the world.</p><p>Earth and Ocean Science is not bad at all. The professor is really passionate about his teaching and makes the lecture very engaging. I guess my satisfaction of this class definitely partially comes from my obsession with hiking.</p><h2 id="Summer-plan"><a href="#Summer-plan" class="headerlink" title="Summer plan"></a>Summer plan</h2><p>Initially, it was challenging for me to come to terms with the possibility of not securing a genuine internship for the summer. However, after speaking with several friends, including those who have landed fantastic internships and those who have not, I began to feel a sense of relief about the situation. For now, I am planning to go to Berlin for a study abroad program and then come back to campus for a full-time software engineer job in a lab. However, I am still not sure if I could do both because of the time constraints. If this works out, I might even be able to go to an F1 race in Austria after my Berlin program!</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202302210104996.png" alt="I love Durian"></p><h2 id="Updates-on-my-website"><a href="#Updates-on-my-website" class="headerlink" title="Updates on my website"></a>Updates on my website</h2><p>In addition to creating a night-mode option for my blog website and adding more content to haojin.li, I have achieved a long-standing goal by finally purchasing the domain lihaojin.com after waiting for three years. Plus, I have configured the GitHub actions to automatically build and deploy both my blog and haojin.li to my servers located in both China and the United States. Despite how it may sound, I am genuinely thrilled to have made these improvements.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202302210103709.png" alt="Pilot Mountain State Park"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This semester has been surprisingly long, in a positive sense.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="school" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/school/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>New semester</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2023/01/28/Reflect-Life-2023-01-28-New-Semester/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2023/01/28/Reflect-Life-2023-01-28-New-Semester/</id>
    <published>2023-01-28T05:16:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>新学期开始了。</p><span id="more"></span><p>很久没有尝试用中文再去记录一些东西，明显得感觉到自己的写作功底下降了不止一些。有时候甚至会忘记一些中文字的写法，想起来着实惭愧。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301280043831.png" alt="很久没有如此惬意地躺在Duke Gardens了"></p><p>不同于高中，我反而很期待大学的每次开学，无论假期有多么的无忧无虑，开学总是我向往的。一是因为能够再见到朋友们，叙叙旧。开学几天和朋友们寒暄总是最有趣的，因为每个人的假期都十分不同，有去旅游的，回家的，甚至还有待在学校做实验的，无论如何我都能感慨万千。二是可以在全新的课程里认识一群新的朋友，新的教授。尤其是这学期的选课，作为计算机专业，我选了两门政治科学，一门计算机和一门用来满足毕业需要的地质学课。我最期待的就是两门政治科学：马克思主义和社会还有政治哲学入门。上学期中国包括世界范围发生的运动彻底改变了我对世界，对政治，对自己的理解，我认为这两门课能够让我更加保持清醒，保持“痛苦”。如果能够坚持得下来，甚至可以兼修政治科学。</p><p>自己身边的朋友，大多数都是计算机或者理科专业，和他们聊天和交流是一种感觉。走进政治课堂，认识新的朋友，和他们沟通交流又是截然不同的一种氛围。并不是说孰好孰坏，但明显两类人是以不同的视角了解这个世界，而我很珍惜这样的机会，让自己能够多方面地汲取知识，了解这个世界。</p><p>开学三周了，至少到现在，比上学期自律了很多。很少出现一个午觉睡过了整个下午的情况，反而因为恰当的课程时间安排，我最懒惰的时间总是正好是上课时间，正好抵消了我自己的惰性。同时，这学期的课程基本都需要签到，对我而言起到了非常积极的作用。同时，我才发现每门课凑巧都有自己认识的朋友，互相促进总是好的。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301280045121.png" alt="在湖边点篝火，看星星在湖中的倒影"></p><p>除了课业之外，我还在想办法找夏天的实习机会。说实话，处在放弃的边缘。或许是因为经济大环境不好，抑或是自己还不够努力，到现在为止的结果却是无法令人满意。我在考虑学校的柏林留学项目，或者待在学校再实习一年，总之不会回国。我觉得父母说的有道理，趁着年轻有机会，多出去走走看看，哪怕旅游也比呆在家里有意义得多。</p><p>当然，这学期成为了fraternity的service vp，自己也很开心能够成为exec的一员。协调沟通所有的volunteer活动却是很繁琐，但当我看到很多成员都来参加活动的时候，那种成就感是难以言喻的。帮助别人确实能够给自己带来极大的快乐和幸福感。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301280046754.png" alt="和朋友们包了400多个饺子，喂饱了我们所有人还有冰箱"></p><p>最近还有些为情所困，但也正因这个契机，让我更看清楚了自己在一段亲密关系里是一个什么样的角色，我想成为什么样的角色，我期望对方是什么样的角色。同时，自己也确实意识到寻求帮助的重要性，当局者迷，旁观者清让我深有体会。很多朋友对于此事给予了我很多帮助，也让我意识到自己在这个方面还是一个连蹒跚学步都算不上的婴儿，需要多经历，不怕失败。无论结果如何，对我而言都学到了很多，我也相信这是一种启示，让我至少尝试去和别人建立更深的关系。</p><p>对于这个学期，没有过多的展望，只想活好每一天，就像之前的每一天一样，不虚度光阴，即为幸福。</p><p>祝好。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;新学期开始了。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Chinese New Year" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/Chinese-New-Year/"/>
    
    <category term="School" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/School/"/>
    
    <category term="APO" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/APO/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Toronto, Niagara Falls, and Cancun!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2023/01/08/Adventure-Metropolises-2023-01-08-From-Toronto-to-Cancun/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2023/01/08/Adventure-Metropolises-2023-01-08-From-Toronto-to-Cancun/</id>
    <published>2023-01-08T19:32:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well yes I flew all the way from the far north to the far south…</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Toronto-to-be-continued"><a href="#Toronto-to-be-continued" class="headerlink" title="Toronto to be continued"></a>Toronto to be continued</h2><p>Toronto is my friend’s base and we started our road trip from here while I didn’t have enough time to fully explore the city before the road trip. Therefore, after coming back from Montreal and Ottawa, I spent almost a week wandering in the city. I basically visited all the must-go places here in Toronto.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110025594.png" alt="Absolutely the city skyline"></p><p>We bought a ferry ticket to one of the island in the Lake Ontario to get the best view of the city skyline. It was freezing cold as expected but the view was amazing. We even stayed for more than two hours waiting for the night view of this charming city.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110030030.png" alt="Cold but beautiful night views"></p><p>After that, of course I need to go up to the CN tower to see the night view from another perspective. I’ve been once here when I was a elementary school kid coming here for a math competition during Summer 2015. That time was daytime while this time I am able to do it at night. As the highest observatory in North America, it is simply stunning. However, it’s definitely not worth it to purchase the extra pricy ticket to the Skypod which is 100m higher than the main observatory because you pretty much see the exact same view even given a huge elevation gain.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110035303.png" alt="Me at the top"></p><h2 id="Niagara-Falls"><a href="#Niagara-Falls" class="headerlink" title="Niagara Falls"></a>Niagara Falls</h2><p>We also drove to Niagara Falls and stayed there for a night. I’ve also been here the last time during the summer and the same got the chance to appreciate the mighty nature once more from a whole new perspective of winter.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110042387.png" alt="Wonderland"></p><p>During the night, there were spotlight for the falls and it was astonishing. Even though we were expecting the entire falls to be frozen, it wasn’t due to a unexpectedly above freezing point temperature. That being said, it was still amazing to see the spotlight combined with the living falls. It was also great as the spotlight changed its color in a dynamic way.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110038679.png" alt="What&#39;s more, there was also fireworks!"></p><p>The daytime Niagara Falls is not as pretty as night’s but still worth visiting. I even found the position to make a time travel photos.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110044272.png" alt="19-year-old me in Winter 2022 and 12-year-old in Summer 2015"></p><h2 id="Why-did-I-decide-also-to-go-to-Mexico"><a href="#Why-did-I-decide-also-to-go-to-Mexico" class="headerlink" title="Why did I decide also to go to Mexico?"></a>Why did I decide also to go to Mexico?</h2><p>It was not on my radar in the very beginning. However, the friend I planed to visit in Toronto proposed the idea and magically he sorted everything out back in early October. Why not then? I thought it would be really cool to experience both the far north and south, the hottest and the coldest within one winter break so I just did it.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110048998.png" alt="I just wanted to show the custom at Cancun airport..."></p><h2 id="XCARET"><a href="#XCARET" class="headerlink" title="XCARET"></a>XCARET</h2><p>The Cancun trip was simple to tell as it was simply amazing and I had my best hotel and park experience at XCARET. I would’ve bought the autobiography book XUEÑOS by XCARET founder Miguel Quintana Pali if I knew how to read Spanish. I was shocked by how beautiful, naturally preserved, friendly all the parks are.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110057552.png" alt="We lived in one of those suites with two amazing sea view balcony"></p><p>That being said, I felt really guilty enjoying all these overly luxury experience. I felt thankful to the friend who made all these happen and brought this wonderful experience but in the meantime myself would definitely choose more economical way to enjoy the vacation here as I do not believe myself deserve this kind of services and material comforts. I would definitely come back with the family or friends I love but with a more reasonable lodging environment. The Luxury is once-in-a-lifetime and is already enough for me.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110058533.png" alt="This show made me a huge fan of Mexican well-preserved culture and talented people"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110059431.png" alt="Panoramic through a scenery tower in one of the most popular parks"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110102702.png" alt="Enjoy the Michelin level taco"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110102027.png" alt="The hotel outdoors without filter or any editing"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110103049.png" alt="Driving the jeep topless in the forest!"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110104464.png" alt="Swim in the Natural Caverns"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110105770.png" alt="Yes, driving the jeep again at night"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110107430.png" alt="Drank too much free cocktails and then rolled on the beach:("></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202301110108115.png" alt="Last free dinner with Chef Teppanyaki"></p><p>And that’s my winter break. Now it’s time to start a new journey with God’s Grace…</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well yes I flew all the way from the far north to the far south…&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="Metropolises" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/Metropolises/"/>
    
    
    <category term="break" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/break/"/>
    
    <category term="Toronto" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/Toronto/"/>
    
    <category term="Cancun" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/Cancun/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Toronto-Montreal-Ottawa Road Trip</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/12/27/Adventure-Metropolises-2022-12-27-Toronto-Montreal-Ottawa/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/12/27/Adventure-Metropolises-2022-12-27-Toronto-Montreal-Ottawa/</id>
    <published>2022-12-27T05:11:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So here I am in Canada.</p><span id="more"></span><p>I always wanted to come back to Canada again after my miserable last visit that I lost all my checked-in luggage due to a mistake at the layover. However, it didn’t stop me from experiencing and appreciating this beautiful country.</p><p>I decided to go there during the winter break mainly because one of my old friend who is in University of Toronto now invited me during the summer. It took a bit efforts for me to get the visa but everything sorted out quickly after that thanks to the help of my friend.</p><p>I know it is not the best time to visit this country as it is freezing cold but I still wanted to go simply for curiosity. At least, there will be much fewer visitors everywhere I go.</p><h2 id="Toronto"><a href="#Toronto" class="headerlink" title="Toronto"></a>Toronto</h2><p>I only spent a day in Toronto, catching up with high school friends mainly. I was really excited to see how they have changed since the last time I saw them was almost 2 years ago. It turned out we never changed. The moment I met them, I felt like going back time to high school, when we dedicated hundreds of hours in VEX robotics together, complaining, debating, practicing, team-working. I would say that is certainly the highlight of my high school life, even plus my middle school time.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270142761.png" alt="My friend and I"></p><p>One of the friend, who I never thought we could be friend, became really close friend with me, at least by my definition. We are just like the people in completely two different world, yet we get along really well. With this reunion, I enjoyed talking to him very much with nonsense jokes and gossips about our high school.</p><p>It was a bit sad when I realized there is not a certain next time about when we will meet again. However I do know we care about each other and wish each other the best of the best. 君子之交淡如水。</p><p>The only agenda for the visitor part is the Royal Ontario Museum, which I personally don’t really like. There is definitely historical significant exhibits inside but they were really fragmented and scattered in my opinion. Therefore for museum rookie like me, I cannot grasp the full beauty and significance of the museum. After all, it is a decent visit while hanging out with friends a bit.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270149066.png" alt="Royal Ontario Museum looks pretty cool for sure"></p><h2 id="Montreal"><a href="#Montreal" class="headerlink" title="Montreal"></a>Montreal</h2><p>I knew nothing about Montreal. I learned from my friend that the entire province of Quebec is speaking French and all the road signs are only in French. I literally became illiteracy over there but didn’t prevent me from experiencing the culture and the city.</p><p>It is one of the best cities I’ve ever visited. The downtown area is full of the vibe of arts and the french romantics. It was having snowstorm when we arrived which I never saw before. A terrible weather for others surprisingly became a first-time experience for me. I very much enjoyed the snow during the first day. Sliding and playing snow on the street was so much fun for me just like a kid.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270148770.png" alt="Sliding on the street"></p><h3 id="Food"><a href="#Food" class="headerlink" title="Food"></a>Food</h3><p>The food is amazing here. We had some great Spanish, French and Chinese food here. Besides Chinese food, the other two exotic cuisine were far better than my expectations. Indeed they look really fancy, but they tasted really well and you can actually get enough to eat at a reasonable price.</p><p>Some of the restaurants also have great vibes with dimmed light and special seat layouts. Frankly, I am never a foodie especially during the trip as I care more about the cultures and the places we go. However, I do have a great impression on the food culture here.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270153215.png" alt="A French Brunch"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270154788.png" alt="And a French Supper"></p><h3 id="F1-Circuit-Gilles-Villeneuve"><a href="#F1-Circuit-Gilles-Villeneuve" class="headerlink" title="F1 Circuit Gilles Villeneuve!"></a>F1 Circuit Gilles Villeneuve!</h3><p>I’ve always been a huge fan of Formula One and here we go! This is the first circuit I’ve been to and it was amazing even at a temperature of -16 degree. I felt extremely excited when walking through the starting grids and the pit lane where I saw on the TV every time with awesome formula one cars passing by.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270156396.png" alt="It looks like a normal street but made me so excited"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270159104.png" alt="The 3rd starting grid"></p><h3 id="Biodome"><a href="#Biodome" class="headerlink" title="Biodôme"></a>Biodôme</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270201174.png" alt="Yes this is in Montreal. It is a indoor full ecosystem of rainforest called Biodôme"></p><h3 id="Notre-Dame-Basilica-of-Montreal"><a href="#Notre-Dame-Basilica-of-Montreal" class="headerlink" title="Notre-Dame Basilica of Montréal"></a>Notre-Dame Basilica of Montréal</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270203105.png" alt="A well-decorated catholic church. We also went there for the Mass during the Christmas Eve"></p><h3 id="Old-Port"><a href="#Old-Port" class="headerlink" title="Old Port"></a>Old Port</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270206953.png" alt="Old Port of Montreal with a famous Ferris wheel!"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270207603.png" alt="A Rockefeller Plaza-style skating rink"></p><h3 id="Mount-Royal"><a href="#Mount-Royal" class="headerlink" title="Mount Royal"></a>Mount Royal</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270208218.png" alt="I could not take out my hand from my pocket for more than 10 seconds because of the coldness"></p><h2 id="Ottawa"><a href="#Ottawa" class="headerlink" title="Ottawa"></a>Ottawa</h2><p>It is also a charming capital with less crowds compared to Toronto and Montreal. We spent a day and a night here with a long walk around the downtown area.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270211325.png" alt="I love the Christmas decorations"></p><h3 id="Parliament"><a href="#Parliament" class="headerlink" title="Parliament"></a>Parliament</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270212233.png" alt="Classic"></p><h3 id="Rideau-Canal-Ottawa-locks"><a href="#Rideau-Canal-Ottawa-locks" class="headerlink" title="Rideau Canal Ottawa locks"></a>Rideau Canal Ottawa locks</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/2023/202212270213463.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So here I am in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="Metropolises" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/Metropolises/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My sophomore Fall</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/12/20/Reflect-Life-2022-12-20-My-sophomore-Fall/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/12/20/Reflect-Life-2022-12-20-My-sophomore-Fall/</id>
    <published>2022-12-20T21:10:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been a bittersweet semester with so many things happening out of control in an unexpected way.</p><span id="more"></span><p>Always, the frequency that I update my blog to some extent could represent my mood during a specific period of time. For example, during last year at this time, I was stressed out with tons of college applications happening on. Apparently, I got into the same situation again with hundreds of internship applications to send out, wait, and be rejected. Apart from that, the classes I took this semester has played a huge role in a huge shift of my value, political understandings and my world view, which might have already changed my life entirely.</p><p>I wouldn’t say it was a better nor worse semester compared to my freshman year. Objectively, I participated in fewer events, clubs and socials while subjectively speaking I learned and grew more internally.</p><p>I could not really have a comprehensive rewind of my entire semester yet there are always something I would never forget and pop up instantly while I am writing this.</p><h1 id="APO"><a href="#APO" class="headerlink" title="APO"></a>APO</h1><p>Since I pledged last Spring at APO with a super random motivation that a Duke alum recommended me to try it out, I have been much more involved and interested in the organization as I thought I would be. I wouldn’t say it is the most important or valuable experience I have, but somehow it leaves to the end after I quitted so many clubs. I simply enjoy being here and doing volunteering works with other Duke students. It might because partially I would like to repay my “guilt” that I had not participated enough services back in high school.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225001953.png" alt="Catan during Pledge Retreat"></p><p>The most unforgettable service event I had this semester was a baseball game for children with special needs. As the Service Chair, it was the first event that I coordinated individually without the help from the Service VP. I was worried about nobody would show up to the event while it turned out to be around 10 people with me bugging everyone within the organization. I was really excited to see so many people coming to the event I coordinated, and most importantly brought happiness to those lovely children.</p><p>In the end of the semester, I was elected to be the Service VP, which means it is time for me to take all the responsibilities of coordinating all kinds of service events. It is a time-consuming works but at the same time it is a well-rewarding job. One of the main side work I have for this winter break is to sort out everything for next semester before it begins. And frankly, I am ready and take it seriously to make sure everything is going to work smoothly in the next semester.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221220162753.png" alt="Book Harvest - One of the many service events I attended this semester"></p><h1 id="Recruitment"><a href="#Recruitment" class="headerlink" title="Recruitment"></a>Recruitment</h1><p>Well, it is tough. I have nothing to say but frustrations. I considered myself well-prepared in the very beginning of the semester and applied countless jobs with such confidence that I would stand out from other candidates. However, things always happen differently. I began to be stressed out, seeing people around me getting so many awesome job opportunities. It reminds me of the last year when I applied for colleges. They gave me the same level of mental burdens and physical fatigues.</p><p>Anyway, my expectation began to shift. Still, I have the backup plan to work for the OIT office on FixIt for the next summer or to go to the bootcamp and study abroad opportunity in Cape Town which many people consider as a scam while I believe it is the best fit for me as I love traveling and see different things all across the world.</p><p>Another main task for the winter is be more prepared and apply more companies, which I will try my best and hope for the best for.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221224235701.png" alt="The only good thing is that I had my 6th visit to Microsoft offices. This time is in RTP"></p><h1 id="My-world-view-shifted"><a href="#My-world-view-shifted" class="headerlink" title="My world view shifted"></a>My world view shifted</h1><p>I have so much to say regarding this. In the classic sci-fi movie The Matrix, the protagonist was asked to choose between the blue pill (Reality) and the red one (Conceived world). I was facing the same choice this semester and I chose the blue pill by accident which was extremely painful and disturbing for me to confront with all the cruel truth.</p><p>It all starts with the trip to Ashvile. I was debating with my friends about the party. I believed in my country and the party to bring the best for the people even given so many disrupted misinformation from the western media. However, I could not rebuttal almost every of his arguments.</p><p>Then, in two humanity classes that I took: Migrant China and Comparative Approach to Global Issues, I learned about the concept of “imagined community” and directly see the life of Chinese migrant workers from the bottom working class through the lens of documentary and so many academic literatures. I was more and more astonished and shocked with more lectures going on. Moreover, as the social movement happening in China, everything add together significantly complicated my views on myself, my country and the world.</p><p>I couldn’t say much or do much about this for now but I do understand one lesson: China is not a superior country compared to US or any countries in the world. Rather, they are inheritly equally problematic.</p><p>A more tangible change for myself is I suddenly realized the significance of liberal arts education and decided to pursue a BA (currently considering political science) besides BS in computer science. Since I do believe science teaches me modern techniques and equips me with powerful knowledge that gives me more and more confidence while learning deeper. On the other hand, social sciences and humanities teaches me all the hard truth and evil appearance. It forces me to take the blue pill and let me confront with everything. I could not escape. I became destablized but a much broader understanding of the world, the real world. This is something I really want to do in my college years even it is hard, and might be useless since it wouldn’t help me in any utilitarian point of view. In a nutshell, I want to be knowledgeable rather than ignorant although ignorance is such a great blessing which rules my life for 19 years.</p><h1 id="MakeNew"><a href="#MakeNew" class="headerlink" title="MakeNew"></a>MakeNew</h1><p>This is my first semester after becoming a Christian. To many extents, I feel more connected with God and my sins. God is showing everything to me at the right moment while letting me to digest and reflect on. I feel extremely grateful and warm with makenew friends all around me. I started to understand the meaning of the church and how kind, selfless, powerful, loving, holy Jesus is. I know God is going to give me more and I will take all to repent. Life is not simply about being a good man. Rather, it is about acknowledging my earthly limitations and striving for the heavenly fruits.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221220163300.png" alt="I LOVE bonfire"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221220163419.png" alt="I don&#39;t why but it looks like cyberpunk vibe"></p><h1 id="Hiking"><a href="#Hiking" class="headerlink" title="Hiking"></a>Hiking</h1><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225000056.png" alt="Kayaking!"></p><p>I just realized how much I love hiking. I planned out my first ever entire hiking trip to Shenandoah National Park and drove 700 miles within 3 days. Nature empowers me so much that I can’t help exploring it as much as I can.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221220161624.png" alt="Blue Ridge Mountains~"></p><p>For the spring semester, I am going to the Mighty 5 National Parks in Utah plus Great Canyon NP with so much excitement in my heart. Also, I found one of my goal of life: finishing the 2k miles Appalachian Trails.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225000421.png" alt="Jump into the Fall!"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been a bittersweet semester with so many things happening out of control in an unexpected way.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Shenandoah National Park</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/11/25/Adventure-National-Parks-2022-11-25-Shenandoah-National-Park/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/11/25/Adventure-National-Parks-2022-11-25-Shenandoah-National-Park/</id>
    <published>2022-11-25T21:14:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was my first ever self-planed hiking roadtrip which turned out to be amazing ever since the very beginning.</p><span id="more"></span><p>I’ve always been a huge fan of the song <em>Take me home, country road</em> by John Denver. Every friend of mine knows how much I’d love to sing this song for no reason randomly. And it would be great to discover all the places mentioned in the lyrics, which is the one and only reason I planned out this Shenandoah trip. “Blue Ridge Mountains, Shenandoah River~”</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225004933.png" alt="My crew"></p><p>I started planning a month ahead in order to book the best hotel and I was simply excited about it since a long time ago. And it turned out all my plannings were necessary and actually helped us a lot on the way because of my familiarity of the park.</p><h1 id="Day-1-Hikes-amp-Sunset-amp-Stargazing"><a href="#Day-1-Hikes-amp-Sunset-amp-Stargazing" class="headerlink" title="Day 1 Hikes &amp; Sunset &amp; Stargazing"></a>Day 1 Hikes &amp; Sunset &amp; Stargazing</h1><p>We set off from Duke at around 7 and wasted 2 hours on breakfast that we hadn’t left Durham by 8:30am. I was a bit reckless during the frist few hours driving since I never drove in North Carolina but I got used to it very quick. Since we were going to the South entrance of the Park which is along the Blue Ridge Parkway, mainly all the road we drove were state roads instead of faster interstates. Nevertheless, it was another kind of enjoyment while you could see the vast ranches with cows, horses and sheep on the way. What’s more, I got a legitimate reason to loop <em>Take me home, country road</em> !</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225005436.png" alt="Three idiots haha"></p><p>We arrived around noon and started our first hike which is called Black Rock. It was a short warm-up trail but with unique piles of piles of rocks in the end of the trail. We climbed to the top of the rock overlooking the mountains.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225004644.png" alt="Black Rock"><br><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225005100.png" alt="Overlook"></p><p>Our second trail is Doyles River Falls which is a bit strenuous with great elevations ups and downs. There are upper and lower two falls and are definitely worth visiting.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225005654.png" alt="Upper fall"></p><p>The sunset was much earlier than we thought. After the second hike, we had half an hour to find a overlook for sunset. Indeed, it took us exactly half an hour to find a perfect outlook. This was the best sunset I had ever seen before. Because of the elevation, we were able to see the entire skyline without any obstructions. The wideness and the richness of the color layers of the sunset was beyond amazing.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225010104.png" alt="Amazing amazing"></p><p>The stargazing was also amazing as we also saw a lot of deers at night in the park. It was freezing cold but I was able to see three fleeting but shining shooting starts which is all I wanted.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225010702.png" alt="A sky full of stars~"></p><h1 id="Day-2-6-hour-trail-amp-Bonfire"><a href="#Day-2-6-hour-trail-amp-Bonfire" class="headerlink" title="Day 2 6-hour trail &amp; Bonfire"></a>Day 2 6-hour trail &amp; Bonfire</h1><p>This day we mainly got one event: climb a mountain along a 6-hour strenuous trail. I never did such a long trail before and I was excited to see how it began. The trail is called Old Rag and is the highest rating trail within the park. The first part of the trail is classic winding some trails which was ok but still takes us at least two hours. We were able to reach a high overlook to see the ranch and mountains in the same frame which was simply marvellous.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225010945.png" alt="The le epic overlook"></p><p>The second part was quite challenging but interesting. It was all about rock scrambles. We were literally rock climbing but in a different way.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225011113.png" alt="The path was even covered by ice"></p><p>Then we arrived at the top of the mountain. IT WAS THE MOST BEAUTIFUL MOUNTAIN TOP. I was able to approach a cliff which really scared me but gave me a once in a life time view of the nature.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225011324.png" alt="Pondering while sitting at the edge of the cliff"></p><p>The last part of the trail was actually the hardest part. After reaching the top, going back to the beginning is hard since the goal was already accomplished. It took us longer for the come-back trail compared with climbing up. However, it was a great experience that we all managed to push ourselves to the limit.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225011714.png" alt="远方"></p><p>This trail inspired me to take on more difficult trails in the future which I am going to do during the Spring Break and my life.</p><p>The last thing we did was bonfire at night. It was miraculously better than I thought with no one having prior knowledge of lighting a fire with woods. We ended up cheating using some chemical liquids but the fire was amazing. With my favorite songs from the speaker, I enjoyed the moment so much.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225012043.png" alt="Cold air with hot fire and shining stars"></p><h1 id="Day-3-Luray-Caverns-amp-Skyline-Drive"><a href="#Day-3-Luray-Caverns-amp-Skyline-Drive" class="headerlink" title="Day 3 Luray Caverns &amp; Skyline Drive"></a>Day 3 Luray Caverns &amp; Skyline Drive</h1><p>We went to a world-famous Caverns in the town of Luray that we lived in. The caverns was much larger than I thought and was definitely worth visiting even you are not interested in caverns in the first place. The most astonishing view for me is the reflection of reef in the water. It looks exactly like two real reefs at the top and the bottom respectively.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225012418.png" alt="Only the upper side is real"></p><p>In the afternoon, we continued to drive on the rest of the Skyline Drive and stopped by a few overlooks to appreciate this great landscape gifted by the nature.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225012615.png" alt="from cloudy to sunny"></p><p>All in all this is one of the best roadtrip I have ever had and I do find I have a great passion in hiking. I always put all my enthusiasm into planning which I believe I am a good planner. I would love these kind of trips happening more and more. If you do read until here, please let me know if you are interested in any roadtrip with me if you are also a fan of either hiking or just simply nature. I promise I will be the best guide you find (exempted from legal liability though haha).</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20221225013430.png" alt="Will see you next time, Shenandoah NP!"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was my first ever self-planed hiking roadtrip which turned out to be amazing ever since the very beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="National Parks" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/National-Parks/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Summer done!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/08/30/Reflect-Life-2022-08-28-Summer-Done/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/08/30/Reflect-Life-2022-08-28-Summer-Done/</id>
    <published>2022-08-30T02:59:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wooooo summer can’t be better.</p><span id="more"></span><p>Since last post, I set off to California for a 23 days vacation. I was beyond thrilled to start the journey and also beyond excited to move forward for the new semester as a sophomore.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828233731.png" alt="Big Sur"></p><p>I remembered it was such a long flight flying over there with one layover. I could not wait to see all my friends who I haven’t seen for an entire year. Shortly after my arrival, I drove the car we just rented to pick up the last friend who were coming by train. That was my first time officially driving in US and I didn’t even realize how to use the foot brake. It took me a while to figure out stopping the alarm from beeping. The night was quite creepy that most roads were closed which were supposed to lead to the train station. Three of us just on the car, happily joking about each other. The moment we successfully found the spot and greet our last friend, it was such a defining moment for our trip. No tears, no dramas but purely happiness of each and every one of us.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828234212.png" alt="Apple Park haha!"></p><p>We started to explore the city of Irvine, which is indeed very nice. I had countless great Chinese food that I believe are even better than actually China’s. Admittedly, they are quite expensive but it was time to spend some money and gain some enjoyment from the delicious food. I never really had any non-Chinese restaurant as I did realize that I have a very typical “Chinese stomachache”. All exotic food are just for fun experience and Chinese food are in effect the food for life.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828233807.png" alt="Black&#39;s Beach in San Diego"></p><p>What’s more, we went to all-you-can-imagine beaches in California. I wouldn’t say they are better than those of east coasts’ but I did get a chance to watch fabulous sunset along the coast. The light, the dark and the shade during the dusk were amazing in all means. The famous 17 miles drive also amazed me with how azure the ocean is and how plentiful the layers of ocean are. It was such a pleasure to drive along this famous road.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828234250.png" alt="Yosemite"></p><p>Talking about the most unforgettable memory from the trip, it must be the entire clear Milky Way with numerous stars in the sky above Sequoia National Park &amp; Kings Canyon. I had never seen that many stars and that kind of sky in my entire life. It was mind blowing. I ended up driving back around 10 and it was dark and scary on the winding mountain roads where not even one car passed by for 50 miles.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828233951.png" alt="Newport Beach"></p><p>Inspired by one of my friend, I became much more adventurous during the trip. I climbed up to the top of the Yosemite Lower Fall, dived into the cold water with normal shirts and shorts. I enjoyed it very much. Also inspired by another friend, the greatness of the nature always reminds me of how great and powerful our God is.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828234327.png" alt="Kings Canyon"></p><p>There are also Humanistic elements along the coast. Solvang, Hearst Castle, Salinas, San Diego they are all great cities &#x2F; towns that bring joys.</p><p>Apart from what I have seen , I also grew in terms of essential life skills. Driving over 2000 miles, handling all housekeeping stuff myself, plan everything on my own, these are all invaluable experiences that cultivate how I interact with the world and be what kind of person.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828234053.png" alt="Santa Barbara"></p><p>A strange feeling I have for the trip is that I not really miss it or wish it could be longer since I do have had everything that can have. I am fulfilled in terms of this matter and won’t regret on anything.</p><p>Also I realize I do love the suburb living styles just as Durham area. I hate SF, LA very much and won’t even consider living near those mega cities if given a choice.</p><p>Alright, it’s time to kick off a new semester and embrace new challenges in academia, life, work and faith.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220828233701.png" alt="Moro Rock"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wooooo summer can’t be better.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Summer almost done</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/07/31/Reflect-Life-2022-07-30-Summer-almost-done/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/07/31/Reflect-Life-2022-07-30-Summer-almost-done/</id>
    <published>2022-07-31T00:16:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The flight to California is just to long to do anything. So why not wrapping up my summer so far.</p><span id="more"></span><p>Less than a month until the next school year. Looking back at the past three months, I have accimplished and grown so much that I would never imagine before everything started.</p><p>The main part of this summer is definitely code plus. I learned so much over the course of 10 weeks. I never built any app or any comprehensive project that could be used for actual users and most of them were just a single program that takes certain inputs and calculates outputs as demanded. FixIt is an actual web application that Duke people could use in the future. I am also very grateful for all the people I met through Code+, who I hanged out with every weekend and karoake all day long. That was such a great experience for me. More than that, Code+ is an actual full-time job that provides me an invaluable opportunity to take a glimpse of what does it look like to work in tech field. I would say it could not be better. I am very determined that software engineer is what I want to be in the future and I dreadfully enjoyed the entire coding and developing process. One core thing I learned from this work is definitely communications and collaborations with teammates, sponsors and stakeholders. To be honest, it was not a very pleasant experience working with some of my collegues but because of their unwillingness to get things done, I got a lot of things done and learned frontend, backend, devops and product design&#x2F;management which are a lot of stuff to learn in 10 weeks. Thus, in the future, I plan to keep working on the project to put it into production to make impacts on the Duke community.</p><p>This summer, I genuinely feel fruitful in terms of what I have gained. Besides technical skills and career goals, I have grown spiritually. I believe it’s God’s will to let me spend the summer with Makenew and let them guide me on my path to faith. I am still confused, scared and self-centered, but I know what is the truth and I have the willingness to move forward to be closer to God and confront my sins.</p><p>Also leetcoding is becoming a habit for me now. I am very looking forward to the recruitment season and hope I could have the offer I want. Especially when one of the DevOps folks in Duke OIT office asked me: “where are you going for internship next year? Google or Facebook?” I was flattered and was really delighted that people see and acknowledge my skills and passion in terms of software engineering. I am confident. Also I am really grateful for one of my friend who are doing mock interview with me every week to help me in every means. I could not be more appreciate his help and guidence.</p><p>In summary, it is the only ever summer I feel like that I actually made some positive learning and progress rather than having pure fun every day and feeling guilty after summer ended. I LOVE this summer and better things will come!</p><p>Looking forwad to what’s going to happen in California.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220731013433.png"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The flight to California is just to long to do anything. So why not wrapping up my summer so far.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Today I become a Christian.</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/07/15/Reflect-Life-2022-07-14-Today-I-become-a-Christian/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/07/15/Reflect-Life-2022-07-14-Today-I-become-a-Christian/</id>
    <published>2022-07-15T03:33:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I become a Christian.</p><span id="more"></span><p>I always imagine this day would come in a natural way that by that time, I have already fully known God and fully admitted  my own sin and how Jesus died on the cross for me. However, this day comes in an unexpected way. I haven’t fully known God nor fully repented my sin but I do have a strong willingness to eager for a meaningful and eternal relationship with God, who I believe is the Creator of the world and us. He sacrifices so much that no human being could bear it. We keep rebelling and disappointing and even killed God. His grace is still there, always there.</p><p>I know every truth that I should know to have a leap of faith. It’s just I haven’t felt it in a strong and powerful way. But I truly believe that day will come. It is frightening, but I would like Jesus to be the center of my life and teaches me how to be a Christian and understand God.</p><p>Promises to keep, miles to go.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I become a Christian.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Summertime 🏖️</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/06/19/Reflect-Life-2022-06-19-Summertime/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/06/19/Reflect-Life-2022-06-19-Summertime/</id>
    <published>2022-06-19T21:05:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s again been a long time since I wrote the last post.</p><span id="more"></span><p>I used to skip blogging because I don’t have a lot things to write during that period of time. However, there are too much these days that I even could not fully experience let alone recording them in written.</p><h2 id="Pre-Code"><a href="#Pre-Code" class="headerlink" title="Pre-Code+"></a>Pre-Code+</h2><p>After coming back from the beach week, I moved to friends’ apartment near west campus. It is the first time ever I lived someplace truly independent. Campus dorm doesn’t count since I could get everything I want within walking distance. Also there are staffs taking care of all housekeeping and tedious logistics things for you.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220619174125.png" alt="View from the floor of the livng room"></p><p>It was nice staying in an independent place, though sleeping on the floor in the living room. I slept unexpectedly really well every night and developed some good habits that I should have had a long time ago. I took a shower every morning to wake myself which I normally did at night since I could not get up in the morning. I continued to cook food for myself but more frequently. I started to practice LeetCode problems every day with friends on Zoom. I kept working in Perkins OIT desk to earn some pocket money.</p><p>In a nutshell, this is the first ever summer I felt like I am being productive instead of doing nothing.</p><h2 id="Code"><a href="#Code" class="headerlink" title="Code+"></a>Code+</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220619174004.png" alt="Moving back to campus"></p><p>It’s Code+ time. To be honest, I have a lot of expectations toward the program. I got kind of disappointed in the first week of Code+ since we attended quite a few extremely entry-level programming classes and useless lectures. Then I started to learn everything we need for our project by myself. It turned out really well.</p><p>Also supporting staffs of the program are really helpful who I learned a lot from. It feels exciting to build an actual website that could help Duke students. I have to say that I enjoy working every day 9 to 5 and debugging all tricky problems I encountered. That sense of achievement has made me convinced and determined to be a software engineer at least in the near future.</p><p>Some fellow participants said I was really smart and the prototype I built was really awesome. But I do believe there’s nothing difficult of what I achieved. I just put all my efforts and I am genuinely interested in software development. It’s nothing like algorithm design or academic researches that I believe require high understanding of knowledge and IQ. Nevertheless, it is an important work that makes differences to people’s life. It is a miniature of amazing high technologies that human has developed. This is exactly what I would love to do. I am delighted that Code+ not only “forces” me to learn skills myself but also makes me confident and determined in software development.</p><h2 id="Cooking"><a href="#Cooking" class="headerlink" title="Cooking"></a>Cooking</h2><h2 id="Hang-out"><a href="#Hang-out" class="headerlink" title="Hang out"></a>Hang out</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220619174304.png" alt="Eno River Quarry: jumping into a lake first ever in my life"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220619174417.png" alt="2022 Commencement: It was freezing cold and I was wearing a single shirt"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220630220224.png" alt="Cooking for my friends!!!"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220630220258.png" alt="Beach is my dream"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220630220415.png" alt="Falls Lake (I should have jumped into the lake again)"></p><p><em>There are just too much to share about my life… :)</em></p><p>Best,<br>Haojin</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s again been a long time since I wrote the last post.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="cooking" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/cooking/"/>
    
    <category term="coding" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/coding/"/>
    
    <category term="summer" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/summer/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The End of My Freshman Year</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/05/02/Reflect-Life-2022-05-01-The-end-of-my-freshman-year/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/05/02/Reflect-Life-2022-05-01-The-end-of-my-freshman-year/</id>
    <published>2022-05-02T03:05:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Standing at the myrtle beach today, I began to reflect on my Freshman journey. </p><span id="more"></span><p>I feel very blessed and fortuated enough to have what I have seen, experienced, and learned from this school year. I never thought my first year in college would be as good as it went through. I was questioning about fate and believed everything is in my control if I worked hard enough. It is just not the truth after experiencing and contemplating on all the things that happened to me. </p><p>I am grateful for my fate. I only had in total a month of online school classes since the covid began. When the virus hitting US, I had come back to normal school mood back in China. As now the virus explodes in China, I have come to US for studying. I still hate Zoom and cannot imagine how my friends went through even all-year-long online courses. I feel like everything in my life is finely presetted so I could have the best outcome as possible. In this sense, I believe myself as a special person as I am certainly being blessed by someone or something that I do not think others have in the same way as I have.</p><p>I am grateful for people around me. I know I have already said this over and over again, but I do genuienly feel this way. Opporuntities, happinesses and thoughts I have, those are all brought by someone else than me. I have met so many talented, passionate, unique and interesting people at Duke that makes me feel previliged to talk to them. I woudld like to list them all but I could not since the list would be super long. It is amazing that how many people have helped me and together shaped me into the person I am today.</p><p>Looking back at the entire school year, there are also countless highlight moments for me. A random dinner with friends, a road-trip, a makenew Friday, whatsoever… But it never is how I grinded out an exam or what is my quiz score on certain tests. I believe, at least for me, grades is the least important thing among all those important things. As long as I have no regrets to myself, I do not think I should put more time on grades. But also, classes are more important than grades as I always tried to do an interesting but harder question rather than easy but boring one. I did that on my phiolosophy final and I felt so good about it that I do not care about the grade anymore as I have spoken what I would like to say and to learn what I want to learn.</p><p>The life is full of adventures ahead waiting for me. Life is fantastic and just best of the best. I kind of understand why 生命 and 生活 are both life in English—因为我像爱生命一样爱我的生活，爱生活一样爱着我的生命。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Standing at the myrtle beach today, I began to reflect on my Freshman journey. &lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>March Madness!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/04/10/Reflect-Life-2022-04-09-Madness/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/04/10/Reflect-Life-2022-04-09-Madness/</id>
    <published>2022-04-10T03:25:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well the true March Madness we lost. But we are the final four!</p><span id="more"></span><p>I never enjoyed watching a basketball game but this time. The game was so tight and intense. Alright, I still don’t like basketball at all. The March Madness is my March Madness.</p><h2 id="APO"><a href="#APO" class="headerlink" title="APO"></a>APO</h2><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220410000218.png" alt="Help cleanning in an addiction treatment house"></p><p>It is a fraternity but it is not. I never intend to join a frat but intend to join an organization where I could do good deeds usually. So I guess this is a perfect choice for me. When the first time I participated APO event, people here were chilled and there was a vibe of chilling in general which I enjoyed a lot. </p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409233840.png" alt="Help packing food for people in need"></p><p>it turned out not bad. I would not say I made a few best friends here but I did meet a lot of good people. I enjoy talking with them and doing silly things in the so-called brotherhood week.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409233737.png" alt="Duke Forest Highway Cleanup: I learned a lot of American beer brands"></p><p>I wish I could be more involved in the group but also I am chilled with everything. Just do good things as much as I can.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409233929.png" alt="I say it is a horse!"></p><h2 id="Cooking"><a href="#Cooking" class="headerlink" title="Cooking"></a>Cooking</h2><p>I AM FALLING IN LOVE WITH COOKING CHINESE FOOD.</p><p>I keep cooking every Sunday night no matter how busy I am. Although each time it took me 4 hours, 5pm to 9pm, to cook, eat and clean. I never thought I could fall in love with cooking rather than eating since I never cooked before and never wanted to cook back in China.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409235029.png" alt="I finally took advantage of the Wok"></p><p>But I was right about myself: if I am pushed to do so, I will do so. I love cooking partly because it is a way to resolve my miss to my hometown (mainly food and my car). Also it is also a great way to socialize with friends as we cook and share together.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409235134.png" alt="Happy Haojin"></p><p>After quite a few times of failures, I finally made the Coca-Cola Chicken Wing successfully. The moment I tasted the wing, I felt an enormous sense of satisfaction and achievement that I never had before. I finally found a true hobby that I am proud of. </p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409235212.png" alt="Dennis&#39;s Stirred Vegetable which was also really good"></p><p>Also when I saw the great amount of oil on the vegetable, I knew it is real Chinese food, this is the real family taste. </p><p>I can’t help imagining learning, trying and cooking all kinds of classic Chinese foods in the coming summer to serve my friends.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409235512.png" alt="BIG Bowl~"></p><h2 id="F1"><a href="#F1" class="headerlink" title="F1"></a>F1</h2><p>This is the sport I feel like March Madness is happening. Now I understand why people are so crazy about Duke basketball since I have the same or even higher level of craziness for F1. Especially this year the game dynamic has completely changed as Mercedes goes down and King’s return of Ferrari. In addition, our proud Chinese driver Zhou Guanyu has grasped the first-ever point in his first-ever F1 Grand Prix. There were so many dramas and will be more in the future. I am even writing my writing101 paper on Formula 1 which is not like other painful writing assignments and I gained a lot of happiness from doing so.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220410000037.png" alt="What a race"></p><p><strong>Life is truly fantastic for me and I enjoy each and every second of it.</strong></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220410000328.png" alt="I just love this picture"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well the true March Madness we lost. But we are the final four!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="F1" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/F1/"/>
    
    <category term="cooking" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/cooking/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>March Madness?</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/04/10/Adventure-2022-04-09-March-Madness/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/04/10/Adventure-2022-04-09-March-Madness/</id>
    <published>2022-04-10T02:05:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a crazy March that has nothing to do with March Madness, but crazier than March Madness.</p><span id="more"></span><p>I know it has been a long time since the last time I blogged. I was telling myself last semester that I could definitely keep blogging at least every week but it turned out not working at all for this semester. It is not because I am having a worse or not-worth-blogging life compared to the last semester. But on the contrary, I am having a great time, great than ever. I would love to blog everything post by post but I failed to do so. Therefore, here is all. </p><h2 id="Spring-Break"><a href="#Spring-Break" class="headerlink" title="Spring Break"></a>Spring Break</h2><h3 id="Washington-DC-Roadtrip"><a href="#Washington-DC-Roadtrip" class="headerlink" title="Washington DC Roadtrip"></a>Washington DC Roadtrip</h3><p>I never thought I could visit DC twice in three months. But here am I, the second time. What different is that I came with makenew folks, which I enjoyed a lot. I had a wried feeling that DC is very familiar to me even more than Beijing. I remember every street I have been to and every artifact in the museum that I have stopped by. Or just because I never visit a place twice within such a short period of time. However, this feeling is amazing partly because you start to appreciate things in the city rather than being surprised by new things. I could tell that I do love the city, the vibe and the history even though it’s short. I have a theory: 500 years is long that 5000 years. Why? Because you share a common perception of things 500 years ago but not for 5000 years’ since they were too old to understand and relate. This is how I feel about my city Xi’an, the most ancient city in China, and DC.</p><p>Two trips together, I have almost visited all the signature museums around National Mall. Frankly, there is no single piece of art or document that is unforgettable to me, but the general feeling is.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409224215.png" alt="Pretending I am the stone man"></p><p>For this trip, I enjoyed sitting in a micro dining room with friends while having <em>not spicy</em> ramen that kept me having a runny nose. It was super fun while carrying Daniel on my back in front of the monument. And I can’t stop laughing at myself that asking Sid to go American Indian Museum together, which has become a joke being told by friends over and over again. Also, making completely nonsense sentences in Nathan’s car with one word per person made me laugh for literally four hours. Most importantly, now I have the experience of sleeping with 10+ people on the ground of an Airbnb house.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409232313.png" alt="Also I was on Daniel&#39;s Back"></p><p>Also I mostly appreciate the time and commitment that makenew people devoted to this trip. I cannot even have a safe plan for four people last time here while they are organizing a trip for 30 people. Relate to what Tim said, I think they are great great testimony of Jesus.</p><h3 id="Asheville"><a href="#Asheville" class="headerlink" title="Asheville"></a>Asheville</h3><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409232125.png" alt="Chimney Rock"></p><p>The first, in the true sense, road trip I have ever had. American nature views are so different compared to China’s. There is an unspeakable difference between them. American mountains are more lively in my opinion while China’s are more awe-inspiring. </p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409230453.png" alt="group photo!"></p><p>The most memorable things: millions of times of <em>Country Road, Take Me Home</em>; Mr. Chou(ugly in Chinese) Diego; 4 hours of walking and almost climbing to see the fantastic overlook of the entire valley since our car couldn’t pass by the annoying bumps; jumping into 50F river and screaming and losing my glasses. I can’t be happier than all the above things brought to me.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409230537.png" alt="In the highest mist~"></p><p>Also an unremarkable but heartwarming scene: A father and 5-year-old boy sitting next to us while watching a mediocre sunset on a mediocre hill. I saw the father and boy interacting with each other in a so sweet way. I am envious of that and just can’t help thinking about what kind of father would I become and imagining all unrealistic family things. Unrealistic but exceedingly desirable.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409231936.png" alt="ZzzZZZzzzZZ"></p><p>Alllso, my birthday. I am so happy that I could celebrate all my birthdays during the break for at least the next 3 years of my life. This is the first birthday I had out of home, which is also the most appreciable birthday I had. I appreciate Mattew’s professional birthday songs and Andy and Min and Jordan’s unprofessional birthday songs. I felt far close to home while far away from home.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409231520.png" alt="Yo!"></p><h3 id="Birthday"><a href="#Birthday" class="headerlink" title="Birthday"></a>Birthday</h3><p>Yes, birthday again. I didn’t expect I would have another birthday on the following day we went back to Durham. I was surprised, moved and grateful. I wish there are words better than “thank you” to say to all the makenew folks. </p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409230635.png" alt="Of course without my glasses"></p><p>Plus I bought myself a gift. A newly released LEGO F1 car. I am not a fan of LEGO but a fan of F1. I enjoyed the process of building it. But this is probably the last LEGO I would purchase since it is so expensive haha. But this one is definitely worth it considering the additional value of emotional attachment.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220409230708.png" alt="Good luck McLaren :("></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a crazy March that has nothing to do with March Madness, but crazier than March Madness.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    
    <category term="break" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/break/"/>
    
    <category term="birthday" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/birthday/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Spring Unwrap</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/03/06/Reflect-Life-2022-03-05-Spring-Semester-Unwrap/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/03/06/Reflect-Life-2022-03-05-Spring-Semester-Unwrap/</id>
    <published>2022-03-06T03:02:01.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We just lost the most important home game today. </p><span id="more"></span><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305233543.png" alt=":("></p><p>It’s only 10 PM but I feel like already 2 AM. The campus is so quiet and everybody I saw was upset with a bitter smile. For me, I am never into basketball and the result doesn’t matter much to me to some extent. However, I can feel the subtle change in my mood in such down campus vibe. A better thing is that it is finally the right time for me to sit down and calm down, reflecting on the past 2 months which I should have done early. </p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305223657.png" alt="Cooking and eating Scrambled eggs with tomatoes &amp; Cola Chicken Wings with friends "></p><p>So many things happened within two months. It was certainly much busier than the previous semester. I joined a new extracurricular club, got a part-time job in the OIT office, read a bunch of esoteric philosophy and sociology papers, pledged a national service fraternity, tried to cook Chinese food every weekend with friends… All of those, I enjoyed a lot, far more than I expected. </p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305223902.png" alt="I am that &quot;secruity guy&quot; next to the door in the APO Induction"></p><p>The world also has been changed a lot. Bad things happened. The Russia-Ukraine War has been imposed huge impacts on each and every aspect of people’s lives, globally. I remember debating with my friends on the roles those world leaders play in such incidents. We could not agree with each other. Nobody could agree with anybody. There are people in the student group chat raising money for the Ukrainian military, joking on “Let’s go Russia”. There are all kinds of people in this world, no matter which part. I have experienced a great sense of hostility and extremity around my daily life, the Internet life, and the lands far away. Nevertheless, I hold an optimist’s view of the world, or at least, for the world I perceive. Recently I have taken up a routine of reading every day before going to bed. From the book A Wavy Life 人生海海, I learned that “The life is not what you have lived for, the life is what you have remembered for”. Relating to my current understanding and experience, I enjoy the moment no matter I stepped up or I gave in.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305224042.png" alt="The BEST dessert place I&#39;ve ever been to, changed my opinion on boba"></p><p>Also, I celebrated the first-ever Chinese New Year away from home. It was refreshing and memorable. I wrapped almost hundreds of dumplings with friends from the church. I bought a lot of classic snacks and just wanted to show my gratitude to this special community. It was the first new year I didn’t watch CCTV Gala. Yet, worth celebrating and remembering for years.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305224219.png" alt="Chinese New Year&#39;s Night!"></p><p>It brings me thoughts onto the religion now. Recently I finished a short introduction book to Christianity by the pastor. It was not mind-blowing but brought up my attention and curiosity to examine the religion and metaphysical questions like what I live for. I always believed in there exists a God who created this beloved world. However, I am still not sure who he is. What does a God truly mean to me, my life, my future, and even my afterlife? As for now, I believe my friends believe for a reason. I believe I desperately want to learn more.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305224348.png" alt="I like the weather so much"></p><p>The most rewarding thing this semester so far is the comments by my writing 101 class professor. This is also the most rewarding class for me this semester. I do feel like I have learned a lot from this class in terms of writing skills and the mindset to perceive the world. As we learned about the labor of sports, contemporary spectator sports is more than an entertaining sport. It is an institution that could suppress humanity, widen inequality and lead to consequences. Everything is doubtful, no matter how good or bad it looks.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305223321.png"></p><p>Life goes on and on~ </p><p>Spring break starts now. </p><p>Warmly,</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220305224808.png" alt="Well, I appreaciate you said that"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We just lost the most important home game today. &lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="cooking" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/cooking/"/>
    
    <category term="Chinese New Year" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/Chinese-New-Year/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First Week of Class</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/01/16/Reflect-Life-2022-01-15-First-Week-of-Class/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/01/16/Reflect-Life-2022-01-15-First-Week-of-Class/</id>
    <published>2022-01-16T03:41:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, it comes to the beginning of another wonderful semester. </p><span id="more"></span><p>Unlike high school time which I genuinely didn’t like switching from sweet and chilled breaks to a busy school semester, I do look forward to the college semester. Probably because it was just so boring during my winter break when I went to Washington DC and came back staying on campus for most of the break. Most importantly, I missed the people I met here including friends and strangers. I enjoyed interacting with people and striking basic conversation with “How are you?”.</p><p>Actually, last week was the first week of class since the semester began last Wednesday. But generally, I enjoyed this whole one and a half starting week though it was completely on zoom. It wasn’t bad at all compared to what I thought would be like. Back in high school, I only had a short experience of online school for a few months and frankly, I learned nothing during that time with all the distractions at home. So I made a judgment that I wouldn’t make it during online learning. However, I did learn a lot and met with new classmates this week via zoom. I had the same feeling of excitement and satisfaction after a long and sometimes internet-lagged zoom meeting. I still got a chance to understand different perspectives on sports, capitalism, philosophy through all my classes which I love a lot based on what’s going on now.</p><p>I keep cooking sometimes this week, mostly because I bought a lot of stuff during winter break and they were going to expire. It was exciting making my own food and feeding myself. It is even more exciting to cook and serve for your friends. We talked, we joked, we laughed while cooking and having meals together. I hope to keep this up through the entire semester.</p><p>There was also a dramatic moment last Saturday when I was mistakenly being told of getting positive on covid while waiting in the line for my first duke basketball game. I called my roommate and we decided to have him stay at a hotel tonight before I figured out this mess of covid. Then I informed all the people I had contact with recently. After that I just sit down alone in my room, self-talking that oh it’s the best time to get covid since I’ll have a great chance of getting recovered before classes in-person, plus sooner or later I’ll get covid based on the roaring of cases. Around 11 PM, I received another email from Duke saying that they are happy to let me know I am not positive due to their mistake. I was relieved at first and then pissed off by their unprofessional actions. I texted all my friends again saying that I am not positive at all and I am gonna sue Duke to get my tuition back even. Anyway, it was a funny experience for me and reminded me I do not want to get covid at all even it’s not as serious as it was. It will affect people around you, persons you care about.</p><p>I met with my friends from makenew a lot this week. I love hanging out with them and sometimes we could talk about some deeper philosophical topics which I enjoyed a lot. I just love getting to know people here and respect them a lot for what they do and what they are trying to achieve.</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220115233017.png" alt="Watching movie &quot;Belle&quot;"></p><p>Well, I don’t know why I decide to write a blog in English this time but I’d like to do that ever since now if my future-me don’t mind. It’s time to struggle with written English and beg to get decent grades in both writing and philosophy classes. </p><p>Best of luck.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally, it comes to the beginning of another wonderful semester. &lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="class" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/class/"/>
    
    <category term="cooking" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/cooking/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2021年终总结</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2022/01/05/Reflect-Life-2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2022/01/05/Reflect-Life-2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93/</id>
    <published>2022-01-05T04:12:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.122Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>很多人称这一年为被偷走的一年，于我而言，却意义非凡。是重大的转折，又仿佛是日出时分，朝霞最亮，最广阔，拥有能够扩展整个天空的野心的时刻。</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Pre-college-Life"><a href="#Pre-college-Life" class="headerlink" title="Pre-college Life"></a>Pre-college Life</h2><h3 id="后申请季"><a href="#后申请季" class="headerlink" title="后申请季"></a>后申请季</h3><p>还记得去年的12月31号的跨年夜，我在利用最后的机会考duolingo。当时压力很大，每天和黑夜作伴，那种黑暗吞噬一切的恐怖感相比文书反复折磨和由于标化成绩给自己带来的不自信感来说不值一提。一直持续到一月末，都过着“生不如死”，绞尽脑汁写文书的日子。不愿再回首，不愿再经历，但我知道那段时光教会了我如何去忍耐，去选择相信，去咬牙坚持下去。</p><p>犹记得学校的元旦晚会，自己当天可能只睡了两三个小时，别人在载歌载舞，我在海量的学校文书里挣扎，电脑屏幕桌面就是密密麻麻的文书一二三四五稿。可能是过的最痛苦的一个元旦了，看着拿到offer的同学欢庆新年，内心隐隐作痛，恨自己。</p><h3 id="Offer雨"><a href="#Offer雨" class="headerlink" title="Offer雨"></a>Offer雨</h3><p>之后该发生的一切都发生了。拿到了不错的offer，在出租屋里声泪俱下，早上七点撕裂的尖叫声在楼道里上蹿下跳，在和母亲的电话里说“我终于证明了自己，我就要让不相信自己的人看一看！”</p><h3 id="毕业季"><a href="#毕业季" class="headerlink" title="毕业季"></a>毕业季</h3><p>拿到offer之后的学校生活很枯燥却又很有趣。上课学习知识的动力是真的没有了，一天最开心的可能就是和同学玩游戏。三天掌握斗地主，七天重拾狂野飙车，我知道每一刻都很珍贵，无论过去当下未来，享受就好。</p><p>人生的第一个大目标算是达成了，有了更多的时间去填补作为一个人的社会属性。我终于可以周末约着同学去吃饭，去看电影，去滑雪，去玩，去社交。在这个过程中，收获了至今跨越整个美洲大陆的友谊，也许是我拥有的第一份真正的友谊。</p><h3 id="暑假"><a href="#暑假" class="headerlink" title="暑假"></a>暑假</h3><p>也可以说我这个暑假是被偷走了的，因为没有干什么正事。参加的夏校让我深刻认识到了自己不是科研的料，自己从未想过我可以做出果断退出的抉择。当然，拿到了驾照算是一件事。当我坐在车里，开车穿行在西安的大街小巷，能够带朋友出去看电影，大晚上把车停在十字路口，驱车三十余公里去农家乐烧烤打麻将，我感觉这是我最有成年的感觉的时刻。我学会了开车，我可以去自己想去的地方了。甚至现在，我并不想家，唯一想的是开车的那种感觉，或者也许是那种让我自身说服已经成长的错觉。</p><p>当然，这段时间最重要的另一件事情就是感恩。去小学初中高中感恩每一位教书育人的老师，感恩高考结束的天才同学们，感恩懵懂时期稚嫩的感情，为一切都算是画上了一个圆满的句号。我知道未来有一天，我一定要向母校捐款，我要让他们以我为豪。总是大家总是拿学校开玩笑，但一切的机遇和经历，都是在这些地方发生的，无论好坏，塑造了现在的我，我必将感恩致谢。这是父母教导我的，是我通过亲身经历所相信的，感恩身边的每一个人，他们让你在时间成丝的现在时成为了自己。</p><h2 id="College-Life"><a href="#College-Life" class="headerlink" title="College Life"></a>College Life</h2><h3 id="Orientation-Week"><a href="#Orientation-Week" class="headerlink" title="Orientation Week"></a>Orientation Week</h3><p>怎么说，超出想象的好。orientation week算是我性格一百八十度大转变的时候，记得刚到学习哦啊还是非常拘谨自卑，真的发现自己是全校英语最差的人了，完全不敢和别人交流。一天晚上被叫出去打牌，我甚至不知道怎么用英文说扑克牌，但那天晚上我真的突然茅塞顿开，不再恐惧，英语张口就来，甚至晚上回去和中国室友狂飙英文。那段时间不上课，有更多的时间去社交，大家交友也不是出于课程抱大腿之类的意图，交友非常地纯粹。我也很感激在那段时间交到了现在非常好的朋友们。牌友变朋友，晚上散步，GADU偶遇church group，每一段看似机缘巧合的经历却构成了我第一个学期的主旋律。</p><h3 id="接下来的日子"><a href="#接下来的日子" class="headerlink" title="接下来的日子"></a>接下来的日子</h3><p>岁月静好，做了中国精准脱贫的presentation，请上课口头禅“shit”的professor吃了flunch，尝试了rowing社团看到了凌晨五点的星辰和日出，通过滑冰由衷地发现了值得欣赏的人儿。一堂课两个半小时的presentation，多到爆炸的数学作业，每次能让我跳脱思想框架的ethics what now program，我真的蛮开心的。</p><p>和church group friends的相处让我开始了解一种信仰，结识了很多朋友，体验了很多传统的美国活动，corn maze，篝火，Marshmallow，beach，一切的一切，我很感恩，很开心，这就是享受生活，发现小小的感动，汇聚成一个又一个幸福绽放的美丽的烟火。</p><h2 id="Winter-Break-Life"><a href="#Winter-Break-Life" class="headerlink" title="Winter Break Life"></a>Winter Break Life</h2><h3 id="Washington-DC"><a href="#Washington-DC" class="headerlink" title="Washington DC"></a>Washington DC</h3><p>一国之都，还是有其独特的风格和底蕴。大理石的纪念堂，若大穹顶的博物馆，欧洲风情的Georgetown小镇，让这座城市别具一格。最喜欢的，其实是这里的食物，其实就是中餐。我们甚至品尝到了习主席访美时的菜肴，还是我的家乡菜。远在家乡万里之外品尝到凉皮肉夹馍的那一刻，眼泪都忍不之掉了下来。我万万想不到半年前大街小巷都能吃到的凉皮如今连汤汁都不愿舍弃。</p><p>这座城市让我看到了美国开国元勋们对于政治理想的追求，也让我看到了这个国家后辈一代一代人对历史的尊敬和浪漫。美国历史不长，记录得却很详细，从无数个博物馆，我看到了无数件文件，图画，物件，影像等等从各个方面佐证独一件事情。</p><h3 id="学做饭"><a href="#学做饭" class="headerlink" title="学做饭"></a>学做饭</h3><p>回到学校，和住在监狱里没有两样。每天唯一的活动就是出去吃饭，晚上打牌。圣诞假期甚至连外出吃饭的权力都被剥夺了，不得不开始自己做饭。从最开始各种苦笑不得的错误，到吃上人生第一个自己红烧的鸡腿，再到连吃3天红烧鸡腿，再到自己煎牛排，煮菜，一步一步，也算是能养活自己了。甚至还有些喜欢做饭，就像父母很早之前所说的，做饭是一项很重要的生活能力，书读的再好，也得学会生活。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220105003323.png" alt="简单的鸡蛋挂面配红烧鸡腿，火腿，胡萝卜和黄瓜"></p><h3 id="圣诞夜，元旦和今夜"><a href="#圣诞夜，元旦和今夜" class="headerlink" title="圣诞夜，元旦和今夜"></a>圣诞夜，元旦和今夜</h3><p>圣诞夜又喝醉了。朋友邀请我喝龙舌兰、打牌。第一次知道需要吃青柠，沾粗盐，然后才是喝酒。喝着喝着就失去了度，也许是圣诞夜太孤独，想着喝醉也无妨。人生第一次喝吐了，在朋友的房间里打滚，在走廊里光着上身乱跑，第二天迷迷糊糊把新买的耳机连同衣服一起洗了，吃了又吐。给一同的朋友们造成了很大的麻烦。但回想起来还是很开心，酒，真的能消愁。</p><p>12月31号晚上，我们一行六人去吃心心念念的火锅。为了一顿火锅，我洗了澡，换了新衣服，期待了两三天。真正吃上的时候，很是满足。半个小时车程，车费接近火锅费用，因此火锅算是一把奢侈。六个背景截然不同的男生在新年夜说着中国话想着怎么最大限度白嫖自助火锅。同样的，格外开心。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20220105003412.png" alt="吃火锅到撑"></p><p>昨天，duke下雪了，我来这里的第一场大雪，也是今年的第一场大雪。出乎意料的，下午雪就完全藏匿了踪迹，无处可循。但雪触及这里的早上，是真实的，美好的。</p><p>今夜，1月4号晚上，母亲的生日，开学的前夜，终于把这份本应在去年完成的年终报告写完了。很期待新的课程，唯一遗憾的是前两周改成了线上授课，只希望一切都会好起来。</p><p>祝好。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;很多人称这一年为被偷走的一年，于我而言，却意义非凡。是重大的转折，又仿佛是日出时分，朝霞最亮，最广阔，拥有能够扩展整个天空的野心的时刻。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Reflect" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/"/>
    
    <category term="Life" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Reflect/Life/"/>
    
    
    <category term="break" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/break/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Washington DC - Day5</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/22/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-21-Washington-DC-Day5/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/22/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-21-Washington-DC-Day5/</id>
    <published>2021-12-22T01:39:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天是最后一天了，没有什么安排，最后自由自在地再感受一下首都的氛围。</p><span id="more"></span><p>今天唯一一件事情就是中午最后吃了一顿中餐，红烧牛肉面。第一次吃面连汤也喝了。</p><p>华盛顿没有纽约那么繁华快节奏，也没有durham那么休闲慢节奏，很喜欢这里欧式一栋一栋联排的小别墅，喜欢只有你想不到，没有你找不到的各种主题博物馆，喜欢美国人对于开国元勋们那种别样的穿越历史的浪漫，一一由建筑表达出来。</p><p>希望不是最后一次来这里，希望下次能够有人可以分享我的观察，经历和热情。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211221210643.png" alt="飞掠五角大楼"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211221210716.png" alt="回到Durham"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天是最后一天了，没有什么安排，最后自由自在地再感受一下首都的氛围。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="Metropolises" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/Metropolises/"/>
    
    
    <category term="travel" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/travel/"/>
    
    <category term="flight" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/flight/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Washington DC - Day4</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/21/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-20-Washington-DC-Day4/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/21/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-20-Washington-DC-Day4/</id>
    <published>2021-12-21T01:39:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天算是比较chill的一天，唯一的行程就是National Zoo。说来惭愧，作为一个中国人第一次看到大熊猫居然是在美国首都。</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="南非美食"><a href="#南非美食" class="headerlink" title="南非美食"></a>南非美食</h2><p>早起吃完早餐，又睡了一个回笼觉。在城市里最幸福的就是每天可以打开yelp选择数不尽的各地美食。我们选择了动物园旁边的一家南非美食。点餐的时候，辣度分为5档，我迟疑了，最后选择了第二辣。尝到鸡肉的第一口，就后悔应该选择最辣的了。但总的来说，鸡肉非常嫩，哪怕是在最里面的部分。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211221204452.png" alt="signature half chicken"></p><h2 id="国家动物园"><a href="#国家动物园" class="headerlink" title="国家动物园"></a>国家动物园</h2><p>动物园和其他经典一样，也都是完全免费的。入园后的前几个景点发现动物都没有出来，可能是天气太冷了，睡着了。但当看到熊猫的时候，一切都值了。真的超出想象的可爱，他们笨拙的步伐，我甚至看到了一个大熊猫爬上树梢，一不小心摔了下来的画面，在地面上翻了几个跟头。众人发出了被萌化的声音哈哈。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211221204815.png" alt="在山坡上的熊猫"></p><p>之后参观了好几个室内的展馆，看到了我见过的最大的鱼，足足有两米长，和人类相当。照片现在再看，确实还有些害怕，这里就不放图片了。</p><p>出乎意料的是，我看到了各种各样的蛇。之前的我是从来不敢看蛇的，连照片都能让我冷汗直冒。而这次，隔着一层玻璃却能够眼不眨心不跳地静静观赏，也许是自己真的长大了？童年最大的恐惧现在看来也都不算什么了。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211221205035.png" alt="动物园留影"></p><h2 id="川陕人家"><a href="#川陕人家" class="headerlink" title="川陕人家"></a>川陕人家</h2><p>我们坐车30分钟才到了这家让我心心念念的餐馆。翻开菜单的第一页写着“本店肉夹馍为习近平主席访美期间指定特供食品”，而吃完的体验也着实证明了确实是款待国宾的上佳菜肴。凉皮和夫妻肺片上来的那一刻，整个人的细胞像是被激活了一样，连平常不喜欢吃的豆芽也都吃得一干二净。能够在异国他乡尝到一口正宗的家乡菜，真的太美好，太难了。</p><p>最后吃的非常饱，从来没有这么感激过一顿饭菜。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211221205403.png" alt="餐厅内的装潢"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天算是比较chill的一天，唯一的行程就是National Zoo。说来惭愧，作为一个中国人第一次看到大熊猫居然是在美国首都。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="Metropolises" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/Metropolises/"/>
    
    
    <category term="travel" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/travel/"/>
    
    <category term="food" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/food/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Washington DC - Day3</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/20/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-19-Washington-DC-Day3/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/20/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-19-Washington-DC-Day3/</id>
    <published>2021-12-20T02:56:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天的行程比较松散，中午才从住处出发。主要徒步浏览了Georgetown还有Georgetown大学。当然，还有最爱的胡辣汤。</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="Georgetown"><a href="#Georgetown" class="headerlink" title="Georgetown"></a>Georgetown</h2><p>从住家步行，大概30分钟就到了Georgetown，类似于国内的历史文化保护区，这里也是颇有历史，很多小国的大使馆就藏匿在众多餐厅酒吧之间，我们看到了阿塞拜疆、巴勒斯坦等等。中午我们去了一个泰式餐厅，准确的来说是酒吧，所以中午并没有几个人在那里就餐。食物上乘，尤其喜欢带有一丝甜味的咖喱酱，与印度咖喱口味泾渭分明，却也各有特色。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219224856.png" alt="颇有欧洲风情的Georgetown，当然我也从未去过欧洲。"></p><p>之后我们前往非常有名的Georgetown Cupcake，排队长度比想象中的短，排队时间却比想象中的久多了。再加上寒风呼啸，着实不好受。但不得不说，cupcake还是非常好吃的，各种味道也有不同的特色，但可能对于我一个中国人来说还是甜过头了。总的来说比较推荐，卖相也很好，拍照自然是首选。</p><h2 id="Waterfront-Park"><a href="#Waterfront-Park" class="headerlink" title="Waterfront Park"></a>Waterfront Park</h2><p>沿着Georgetown一路下坡，就到了河边，景色不能说很美，但给人一种非常沉寂，放空的感觉。无意间我们发现公园尽头的建筑物就是著名的水门事件发生地，美国民主党总部水门综合大楼。岸边有很多海鸥，甚至有一个还短暂停在了栏杆上，可惜我没反应过来拍照，海鸥就飞走了。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219225247.png" alt="水门大楼和右侧被头挡住的肯尼迪艺术中心，晚上会有七彩的灯光投射"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219225511.png" alt="应该是海鸥吧"></p><h2 id="Georgetown-University"><a href="#Georgetown-University" class="headerlink" title="Georgetown University"></a>Georgetown University</h2><p>继续走路，来到了乔治城大学。其实这个学校和我们学校有很多的相似之处，比如标志性建筑都是比较复古的建筑物，且都有教堂。学校给我的感觉是非常紧凑，教学楼、音乐厅、宿舍都无序有机地坐落在高度上下起伏的校园里。校园里甚至还有一片墓地。同行的朋友都认为这里的设施比较新，比duke好多了，但我却认为还是duke好，建筑物规规整整地分布在校园里，给人以不争不抢的感觉。有崭新的教学楼，也有想我的宿舍一样的老建筑物，但我似乎是习惯了，出来参观其他学校才发现竟也爱上了自己的学校，对其他学校完全没有感觉。</p><div class="justified-gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219225541.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219230033.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219230049.png"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219230114.png"></p></div><h2 id="胡辣汤"><a href="#胡辣汤" class="headerlink" title="胡辣汤"></a>胡辣汤</h2><p>受到学长的邀请，去他家吃他自己做的胡辣汤。不得不说，油泼辣子和那股浓重的胡椒味，让我想起了家乡。万里之外异国他乡，能够拜访来自同一个小地方的学长，于我而言真的是一种幸运。希望未来还有机会再见。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219231020.png" alt="与学长的合影"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天的行程比较松散，中午才从住处出发。主要徒步浏览了Georgetown还有Georgetown大学。当然，还有最爱的胡辣汤。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="Metropolises" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/Metropolises/"/>
    
    
    <category term="travel" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/travel/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Washington DC - Day2</title>
    <link href="https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/19/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-18-Washington-DC-Day2/"/>
    <id>https://blog.haojin.li/2021/12/19/Adventure-Metropolises-Washington-D-C-2021-12-18-Washington-DC-Day2/</id>
    <published>2021-12-19T04:55:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-02T05:15:44.118Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天混迹于各个博物馆之间，算是把美国的历史全方位各角度体验了一番，颇有收获。</p><span id="more"></span><h2 id="International-Spy-Museum"><a href="#International-Spy-Museum" class="headerlink" title="International Spy Museum"></a>International Spy Museum</h2><p>受朋友的推荐，早早预订了间谍博物馆的门票，其实这也是唯一一个需要收费的博物馆。整个浏览穿插着一些交互式的游戏，每个人都有一张id卡，会记录你的选择并在最后生成总结。总的来说，噱头大于实际意义，但仍是富有创意。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219215651.png" alt="我的间谍ID卡，中间丢了一次，见到了别人的。比较遗憾最后没有收到自己准确的统计"></p><p>博物馆里看到了很多真实的，用于实战的间谍设备，伪装设备还有真人轶事。尤其佩服美国人的自嘲精神，甚至揭露了很多美国情报组织的dirty work。另外感到意外的，还有博物馆陈列了大量前苏联的装备，甚至在这一个博物馆里，你就能感受到强烈的冷战氛围。两个大国的角逐博弈，成为了众多博物馆的主题或者说是副标题。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219220605.png" alt="KGB行动"></p><p>影响最深的还是乌克兰前总统经过KGB投毒之后毁容的照片，查询中国情报机构显示“Unavailable”，法航在飞往纽约的商务舱上安装窃听装置，现在听起来甚至都有些令人发笑，但这些确实实实在在发生过的历史，着实令人感到历史的魅力，以及保存博物的意义，哪怕是博后人一笑，也让这些事迹通过各种方式保存了下来。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219220624.png" alt="美苏对峙"></p><h2 id="National-History-Museum"><a href="#National-History-Museum" class="headerlink" title="National History Museum"></a>National History Museum</h2><p>在有恐龙化石和一群小朋友的Natural history museum和National history museum里，我们选择了national history museum. 毕竟恐龙化石在哪里都能看到，美国自己诉说陈列的历史只有在这里能看到。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219220903.png" alt="门前合影"></p><p>我们参观的第一个主题展，就是美国的战争史，从独立战争讲起。而这些内容，我们或多或少在致之前的spy museum还有昨天的国家图书馆，华盛顿纪念碑都已经阅读到、接触到了数遍。个人来讲，确实感觉到美国历史时间跨度之短，重要的事件究极归纳也就几件，来来回回反反复复地在各种博物馆通过不同的实物、方式讲述。当然，我能深刻地感受到美国人对历史的尊重和保护，短短一个事件，他们能从每一个维度作证、讲述、纪念和宣扬，这可能是我们中国做不到的，或许是因为意识不到位，亦或许只是历史长河漫漫罢了。</p><p>总的来说还是值得观看的，印象比较深刻的是美国总统和第一夫人展，展出了很多件不同第一夫人的礼服，于我而言算是一桩奇闻逸事。还有美国公民展，讲述了美国人对于自己身份的解读以及投票权的宣传。规模较小的钱币展也颇有意思，在那里你能看到面值十万元的美元钞票。</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219221644.png" alt="曾经流通过的大额美钞"></p><h2 id="National-Archive"><a href="#National-Archive" class="headerlink" title="National Archive"></a>National Archive</h2><p>因为独立宣言原件保存于此而慕名而来。这是我们参观的所有博物馆当中唯一禁止在整个馆内照相的。看到了很多佐证美国历史，具有历史意义的书信、契约以及其他文本形式的记录。</p><p>存放宪法和独立宣言原件的地方是一个单独的地方，非常宏伟的拱形天花板，偌大的圆形展厅内唯一的陈列物就是这些已经很难看清字迹、保存在特殊光线照射的玻璃罩内的文件了。同样的，虽然看不懂几个字，却也为这些文件能够保存至今而感到震撼，美国的立国之本就在我的面前，数百年前美国开国元勋们的字迹在我面前呈现，作为一个中国人，总结这几天的博物馆之旅，说实话我可能还无法理解美国的价值观，但我表示尊重。</p><h2 id="Shopping-Mall"><a href="#Shopping-Mall" class="headerlink" title="Shopping Mall"></a>Shopping Mall</h2><p>因为好友来自这里，他驱车来接我们前往pentagon city的一个shopping mall吃饭。非常巧地遇见了之前yelp上随机点开的中餐馆，于是便进入就餐。最开始我害怕外国友人吃不惯中餐炒鸡蛋，但看好友一盘子米饭解决得干干净净，我也是十分开心。来这里，明显能感觉到不是所有人都喜欢吃中餐的，完全不是国内宣传的那个样子，吃中餐的还是中国人。我们瞧不起异域的食物，他们亦是。所以看到好友的反应，我才松了口气，没有让他感到不舒服。</p><p>之后他请我吃了他最爱的类似于烤面包条的东西，具体的名字我又忘了，但这些都不重要，我是真心能感受到和好友的距离一下子拉近了很多，我们种族不同，甚至如果不是duke，一辈子都不可能有交集。他能够开车接送我们，给我们参谋dc的旅行计划，我感到非常地感激。最后他把我们送到家，专门说想和我照一张相，我真的很是感动。我知道，这是值得深交，未来一辈子的朋友。我们有不同的文化，不同的信仰，不同的肤色，甚至不同的爱好，但我们冥冥之中有一无法言说的地方相通，让我们成为了朋友。祝他寒假一切顺利，来年校园再见！</p><p><img src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image//duke/20211219223054.png" alt="我和好友"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;今天混迹于各个博物馆之间，算是把美国的历史全方位各角度体验了一番，颇有收获。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Adventure" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/"/>
    
    <category term="Metropolises" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/categories/Adventure/Metropolises/"/>
    
    
    <category term="travel" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/travel/"/>
    
    <category term="museum" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/museum/"/>
    
    <category term="friend" scheme="https://blog.haojin.li/tags/friend/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
