<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TOEFL on Haojin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/toefl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TOEFL on Haojin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>@2018-2023 Haojin Li</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 23:12:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/toefl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021年终总结</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 23:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;很多人称这一年为被偷走的一年，于我而言，却意义非凡。是重大的转折，又仿佛是日出时分，朝霞最亮，最广阔，拥有能够扩展整个天空的野心的时刻。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>申请季的选择</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-04-20-%E7%94%B3%E8%AF%B7%E5%AD%A3%E7%9A%84%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-04-20-%E7%94%B3%E8%AF%B7%E5%AD%A3%E7%9A%84%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;申请季结束了，彻底结束了，终于终于可以松一口气了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;短短的两个月，却充满着压力、痛苦与崩溃边缘的徘徊。也算是成人之际，社会现实给我上的一课吧。我认识到了真正的冷暖，好坏与纠葛。这远是超乎我所想象的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很庆幸，总算有了好结果，春光明媚。杜克大学是我的最终选择，也是我最平静的选择。难忘的恰不是这次抉择，而是第一次给予我信心与肯定的那个早晨。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;准时起床，洗漱完毕，穿好衣服，双手合十，像极了一个虔诚的信徒，却不知道信的是什么。或许是自己，又是家人。打开伯克利的portal，平静地登陆，&lt;code&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/code&gt;赫然写在屏幕的中间，我怔住了。右手食指颤抖着滑了几下鼠标滚轮。确定了，是真的，我被伯克利录取了！没有人能想象我有多么激动，甚至一分钟前的自己也无法想象。我开始呐喊，尖叫，朝着屏幕，朝着窗外，朝着接通电话的母亲那端。我要让看不起我的人，失信于我的人，放弃于我的人看一看，无论如何，我做到了。我不管，我做到了。我想打破每一扇窗户，我想更大声地喊出来，我想让所有的所有都听见。我就是这么挣脱理性。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Season</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-01-10-i-ve-never-been-so-tired.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 17:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-01-10-i-ve-never-been-so-tired.md/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, long time no see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short trip to Beijing</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-10-31-a-short-trip-to-beijing.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 22:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-10-31-a-short-trip-to-beijing.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month is really a busy month. Writing essays for application, preparing for TOEFL, learning school courses and participating in Yau Science Awards really stressed me a lot. I feel like I have never been busy as much as now. It&amp;rsquo;s not only about my academic works, since I need to consider many other things that are simple but costs tons of time. All things combined,it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge for me and I need to and have to admit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;coming-to-beijing&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Coming to Beijing &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week long prepare with my mentor, reviewing my paper and debugging my neural network model, I came to Beijing for semifinal of Yau Science Award(Computer) yesterday. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve been to many places without my parents, I was accompanied with teachers or schoolmates. This trip is truly the first trip that I went alone. To be honest, I even was a little nervous at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything went OK the first day. Arriving by bullet train, I took 3 subway lines to go to my hotel next to Tsinghua University. The hotel is fine but I booked a room without windows for cheaper price. However, it was really a awful experience that I felt unwell staying at the room. (I swear I would never book a room without room again) So I decided to go to the university for checking the route in advance just in case that I might get lost the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good impression of Beijing based on previous visits. No exception, it&amp;rsquo;s the same this time. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a prejudice or something else. Anyway, I don&amp;rsquo;t like this city. It imposes bad feeling to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>八佰 The Eight Hundred</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-22-%E5%85%AB%E4%BD%B0-the-eight-hundred.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-22-%E5%85%AB%E4%BD%B0-the-eight-hundred.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;before&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Before &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll have a TOEFL test to take and I chose to hang out with my friend and see a movie. All because I was too anxious about the test. I am trying my best to relax and smooth my nerve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supposedly we were going to see Harry Porter since I never watched the series before and it&amp;rsquo;s a good chance for me to take a look. However, we decided to see the Eight Hundred after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before watching, I have no knowledge about the movie. I was sitting in the second row in the theater which is my first time to sit so close that I need to raise my head to see the full screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-feeling&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;My Feeling &lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech at Foundation Class</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-07-16-speech-at-foundation-class.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-07-16-speech-at-foundation-class.md/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Final Exam</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-06-29-chinese-final-exam.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-06-29-chinese-final-exam.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;局促的咨询室里，有升学指导老师、母亲和他，还有从始至终都没有动过的三杯水。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“老师好，我叫李昊锦，在西安高新第一中学国际班就读，我喜欢计算机，我是……”，他像是背顺口溜一样，一个绊子都没有，非常流利地在母亲和老师面前做了自我介绍。与其说是他在说话，不如说他的嘴巴在发声。这一番话他不知讲了多少遍，在多少个局促的教室里，对着多少初次见面的老师，当然还有每次都陪着的他的母亲，不，他陪着的母亲。他明白自己不能惹母亲生气，每一次都极不情愿地答应与母亲去各种中介办公室交流谈话，而母亲每次都会说这是最后一次，以后他都不用去了。像极了小时候父母哄孩子喝苦涩的中药，但最终都是为了孩子好。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore Stanford Website</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-03-28-explore-stanford-website.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-03-28-explore-stanford-website.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lead&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Lead &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to begin my application. These days my mother is trying to find professional counselors who can be helpful in the course of my application. Also, I know the most important thing is myself. I need to be prepared first and make choice finally. So that&amp;rsquo;s the reason why I am doing this, looking for useful information from several college websites. Here is the first one, that many peers including I admire the most: Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will mark and reorganize some points mentioned in the intro which I think is useful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer vacation starts now</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-07-08-summer-vacation-starts-now.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-07-08-summer-vacation-starts-now.md/</guid>
      <description>A colorful semester has gone A lot of words I want to say… This period of time I studied and lived in International Course Campus really impressed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIT REFRESH</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-03-10-hit-refresh.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-03-10-hit-refresh.md/</guid>
      <description>It’s my first blog in English.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
