<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>school on Haojin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in school on Haojin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>@2018-2023 Haojin Li</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:13:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>One third passed</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-02-21-one-third-passed.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-02-21-one-third-passed.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This semester has been surprisingly long, in a positive sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New semester</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-01-28-new-semester.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-01-28-new-semester.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;新学期开始了。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My sophomore Fall</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-12-20-my-sophomore-fall.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 16:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-12-20-my-sophomore-fall.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a bittersweet semester with so many things happening out of control in an unexpected way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer done!</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-08-28-summer-done.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 22:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-08-28-summer-done.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wooooo summer can&amp;rsquo;t be better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer almost done</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-07-30-summer-almost-done.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 20:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-07-30-summer-almost-done.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The flight to California is just to long to do anything. So why not wrapping up my summer so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of My Freshman Year</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-05-01-the-end-of-my-freshman-year.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 23:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-05-01-the-end-of-my-freshman-year.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Standing at the myrtle beach today, I began to reflect on my Freshman journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Unwrap</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-03-05-spring-semester-unwrap.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 22:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-03-05-spring-semester-unwrap.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We just lost the most important home game today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Week of Class</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-01-15-first-week-of-class.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 22:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-01-15-first-week-of-class.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, it comes to the beginning of another wonderful semester.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021年终总结</title>
      <link>/posts/2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 23:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2022-01-01-2021%E5%B9%B4%E7%BB%88%E6%80%BB%E7%BB%93.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;很多人称这一年为被偷走的一年，于我而言，却意义非凡。是重大的转折，又仿佛是日出时分，朝霞最亮，最广阔，拥有能够扩展整个天空的野心的时刻。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Washington DC - Day3</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-19-washington-dc-day3.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 21:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-19-washington-dc-day3.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;今天的行程比较松散，中午才从住处出发。主要徒步浏览了Georgetown还有Georgetown大学。当然，还有最爱的胡辣汤。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Week</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-12-06-final-week.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 15:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-12-06-final-week.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;从纽约回来之后，立马就进入了期末考试周。周二回来，周五就进行了第一场期末考试，时间过的真快。但确实是不太适应Thanksgiving和Winter break间隔如此之近。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York City - Day3</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-27-new-york-city-day3.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 23:17:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-27-new-york-city-day3.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;出人意料，这是我第一次觉得旅游的时光过的好慢，每天都游历了无数，结识了无数，感悟了无数。今天是第三天，也是想对来说较平淡的一天，却也是有额外的小确幸。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>随记</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-11-14-%E9%9A%8F%E8%AE%B0.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-11-14-%E9%9A%8F%E8%AE%B0.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;哇，不知不觉就已经快到期末了。回顾这一学期，真的是经历了非常多的第一次。但或许还不是做总结的时候，就先从这周开始吧。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloween</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-10-30-halloween.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 02:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-10-30-halloween.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;希望能坚持每周都记录下去吧。自从上次开始，重拾写博客之后，内心总是惦记着。写着看。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>申请季的选择</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-04-20-%E7%94%B3%E8%AF%B7%E5%AD%A3%E7%9A%84%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-04-20-%E7%94%B3%E8%AF%B7%E5%AD%A3%E7%9A%84%E9%80%89%E6%8B%A9.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;申请季结束了，彻底结束了，终于终于可以松一口气了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;短短的两个月，却充满着压力、痛苦与崩溃边缘的徘徊。也算是成人之际，社会现实给我上的一课吧。我认识到了真正的冷暖，好坏与纠葛。这远是超乎我所想象的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很庆幸，总算有了好结果，春光明媚。杜克大学是我的最终选择，也是我最平静的选择。难忘的恰不是这次抉择，而是第一次给予我信心与肯定的那个早晨。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;准时起床，洗漱完毕，穿好衣服，双手合十，像极了一个虔诚的信徒，却不知道信的是什么。或许是自己，又是家人。打开伯克利的portal，平静地登陆，&lt;code&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/code&gt;赫然写在屏幕的中间，我怔住了。右手食指颤抖着滑了几下鼠标滚轮。确定了，是真的，我被伯克利录取了！没有人能想象我有多么激动，甚至一分钟前的自己也无法想象。我开始呐喊，尖叫，朝着屏幕，朝着窗外，朝着接通电话的母亲那端。我要让看不起我的人，失信于我的人，放弃于我的人看一看，无论如何，我做到了。我不管，我做到了。我想打破每一扇窗户，我想更大声地喊出来，我想让所有的所有都听见。我就是这么挣脱理性。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>小小少年</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-03-20-%E5%B0%8F%E5%B0%8F%E5%B0%91%E5%B9%B4.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 21:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-03-20-%E5%B0%8F%E5%B0%8F%E5%B0%91%E5%B9%B4.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;好久没有这么强烈的表达欲了，又想记录些什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;自己平常是从不会看b站的，b站总会给我一种过度娱乐化的感觉，自己也只有平常亟需要纯粹的搞笑视频来放松的时候，才会点开b站。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当然，不可否认我也是跟着b站的学习视频才学了java，顺利拿到了AP CSA 5分。但今天无意点开的一个视频，着实改变了我的认知。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看到《小小少年》的封面像极了VEX机器人，我便点了进去。原来是FRC，自己也了解过一些，这是一项比VEX更加烧钱，耗费时间精力但收获更大的国际赛事。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;影片开始，人大附中的名号遍不绝于耳。我开始习惯性地批判起来：为何这部纪录片要关注宇宙第一高中？这样的教育资源和机会是绝大多数的同龄人所无法触及的，我不明白这个影片的意义在哪里。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;说起来也奇怪，不知不觉我就完全将这种想法抛在了脑后，更多的，是对镜头内容产生的深深的共鸣。影片中的程序员，像极了我的经历。诚然我深知自己不是可以和他比肩的天才少年，但我们有着相同的热爱，相同的遭遇，解决过类似的问题，享受过那份独属于我们的成就感。当然，还有另外一位天才，机械结构搭建的妙手。我脑海里闪过了很多身边的人，向他一样，却又不够像他。就像我不够像第一位天才一样。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Spring Festival with Family</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-02-27-last-spring-festival-with-family.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 23:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-02-27-last-spring-festival-with-family.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year of OX, the last Spring Festival I could spend time with family members together. In my childhood memory, the New Year was full of happiness, mostly sounds of firecrackers&amp;hellip; However, as growing up I find less and less interest and meaningful this traditional festival is. It soon became a period of blank. Nothing much I could do. Yet, this year, is completely different for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom was the first person reminded me of the importance of this year. She planned a lot of places to go where we never had available time to visit together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Season</title>
      <link>/posts/2021-01-10-i-ve-never-been-so-tired.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 17:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2021-01-10-i-ve-never-been-so-tired.md/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, long time no see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Robot Contest Finals</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-12-08-world-robot-contest-finals.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 23:12:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-12-08-world-robot-contest-finals.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was revised on March 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-short-break-during-the-application-season&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;A short break during the application season &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it comes, the application seasion, full of tension, sadness and happiness. At this time, just after finsihing submitting all UC applications, I decided to join this competiton held in Foshan, Guangdong, which is a prosperous city around the Guangzhou. It is a short break for me, for I have some time to reflect the early application season including EA and UC and better think how could I improve in the future. Also, I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken any VEX competition for almost a year due to the COVID. It is the best time for me to catch up with this brand new season and implement my new-learned knowledge in real match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;



  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;mx-auto my-0 rounded-md&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/declan-haojin/blog-image@master/HaojinMacBookPro/image-20210305234436333.png&#34; alt=&#34;image-20210305234436333&#34; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short trip to Beijing</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-10-31-a-short-trip-to-beijing.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 22:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-10-31-a-short-trip-to-beijing.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month is really a busy month. Writing essays for application, preparing for TOEFL, learning school courses and participating in Yau Science Awards really stressed me a lot. I feel like I have never been busy as much as now. It&amp;rsquo;s not only about my academic works, since I need to consider many other things that are simple but costs tons of time. All things combined,it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge for me and I need to and have to admit it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;coming-to-beijing&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Coming to Beijing &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week long prepare with my mentor, reviewing my paper and debugging my neural network model, I came to Beijing for semifinal of Yau Science Award(Computer) yesterday. Though I&amp;rsquo;ve been to many places without my parents, I was accompanied with teachers or schoolmates. This trip is truly the first trip that I went alone. To be honest, I even was a little nervous at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything went OK the first day. Arriving by bullet train, I took 3 subway lines to go to my hotel next to Tsinghua University. The hotel is fine but I booked a room without windows for cheaper price. However, it was really a awful experience that I felt unwell staying at the room. (I swear I would never book a room without room again) So I decided to go to the university for checking the route in advance just in case that I might get lost the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a good impression of Beijing based on previous visits. No exception, it&amp;rsquo;s the same this time. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s a prejudice or something else. Anyway, I don&amp;rsquo;t like this city. It imposes bad feeling to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Exercises</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-30-physical-exercises.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-30-physical-exercises.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 28th, I went to a military training base in rural area of my city with my fellow students. Originally, I thought it would be a tough time based on all my past formidable experience with such training. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take it anymore during my time in both middle and high school. I took a trip and had computer science classes instead. A fun fact is that I became the whitest among my class after they coming back from training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from worry, excitement also haunted around me because it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time to have a training. The result turned out it didn&amp;rsquo;t let me down and I really learned a lot from this fantastic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-team-leader&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Being a team leader &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying my best to be the team leader is always my style, especially participating in a short-time camp. I frimly deem it&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity to promote and improve myself. Then I became the leader of group 6 without any hesitate. I deeply know that I am lack of leadership and most important, the decisive personality. This time I failed again on improving that. Everytime I become a leader in a program, unfortunately, I never felt improvement in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I believe I did great a great job. Organizing the team, encourging everyone doing high-altitude program and cimmitting myself to everything I can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>八佰 The Eight Hundred</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-22-%E5%85%AB%E4%BD%B0-the-eight-hundred.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 18:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-22-%E5%85%AB%E4%BD%B0-the-eight-hundred.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;before&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Before &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;ll have a TOEFL test to take and I chose to hang out with my friend and see a movie. All because I was too anxious about the test. I am trying my best to relax and smooth my nerve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supposedly we were going to see Harry Porter since I never watched the series before and it&amp;rsquo;s a good chance for me to take a look. However, we decided to see the Eight Hundred after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before watching, I have no knowledge about the movie. I was sitting in the second row in the theater which is my first time to sit so close that I need to raise my head to see the full screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-feeling&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;My Feeling &lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech at Foundation Class</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-07-16-speech-at-foundation-class.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-07-16-speech-at-foundation-class.md/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Final Exam</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-06-29-chinese-final-exam.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-06-29-chinese-final-exam.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;局促的咨询室里，有升学指导老师、母亲和他，还有从始至终都没有动过的三杯水。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“老师好，我叫李昊锦，在西安高新第一中学国际班就读，我喜欢计算机，我是……”，他像是背顺口溜一样，一个绊子都没有，非常流利地在母亲和老师面前做了自我介绍。与其说是他在说话，不如说他的嘴巴在发声。这一番话他不知讲了多少遍，在多少个局促的教室里，对着多少初次见面的老师，当然还有每次都陪着的他的母亲，不，他陪着的母亲。他明白自己不能惹母亲生气，每一次都极不情愿地答应与母亲去各种中介办公室交流谈话，而母亲每次都会说这是最后一次，以后他都不用去了。像极了小时候父母哄孩子喝苦涩的中药，但最终都是为了孩子好。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News Report</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-04-17-news-report.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 15:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-04-17-news-report.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;student-based-online-community&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Student Based Online Community &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-under-the-epidemic&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Background: Under the Epidemic &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia, 2019 (COVID-19) is an infectious disease caused by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2). The disease was first identified in December 2019 in Wuhan, the capital of China&amp;rsquo;s Hubei province, and has since spread globally, resulting in the ongoing 2019–20 coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Berkeley</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-04-12-discover-berkeley.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-04-12-discover-berkeley.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lead&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Lead &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one in my &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover College Series&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berkeley, the college that is close to my dream in California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The following are some quotes and main point I referred from official website of Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore Stanford Website</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-03-28-explore-stanford-website.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-03-28-explore-stanford-website.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lead&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Lead &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to begin my application. These days my mother is trying to find professional counselors who can be helpful in the course of my application. Also, I know the most important thing is myself. I need to be prepared first and make choice finally. So that&amp;rsquo;s the reason why I am doing this, looking for useful information from several college websites. Here is the first one, that many peers including I admire the most: Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will mark and reorganize some points mentioned in the intro which I think is useful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educated -- Reading Journal</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-03-16-reading-journal.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 16:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-03-16-reading-journal.md/</guid>
      <description>Why I chose this book to read I get an inexplicable feeling about my life recently and books help me a lot in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer vacation starts now</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-07-08-summer-vacation-starts-now.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-07-08-summer-vacation-starts-now.md/</guid>
      <description>A colorful semester has gone A lot of words I want to say… This period of time I studied and lived in International Course Campus really impressed me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our fantastic bridge -- Bridgination</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-06-21-our-fantastic-bridge-bridgination.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-06-21-our-fantastic-bridge-bridgination.md/</guid>
      <description>So, it’s time to prepare for the final exam and enjoy the only moment we have in fundation period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My article was published in the school newspaper!</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-29-my-article-was-published-in-the-school-newspaper.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 16:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-29-my-article-was-published-in-the-school-newspaper.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary-of-2019-vex-worlds-championship&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Summary of 2019 VEX Worlds Championship &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;vex-2019世锦赛总结&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;VEX 2019世锦赛总结 &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
  href=&#34;http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/large/bea775ably1g495bkhmssj22a13a44qr.jpg&#34;
  
  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer noopener&#34;
&gt;



  &lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img class=&#34;mx-auto my-0 rounded-md&#34; src=&#34;http://ww1.sinaimg.cn/large/bea775ably1g495bkhmssj22a13a44qr.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;难忘的一次经历。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;久别重逢&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;久别重逢 &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;作为刚刚转入国际班的新生，我很荣幸被韩老师选中参加VEX2019世锦赛。赛前，有激动、欣喜，也有紧张与茫然。VEX，于我而言是一个既熟悉又陌生的竞赛项目。初中时在韩老师的带领下参加了“一网打尽”和“星光璀璨”两个赛季，也收获了很多。本以为与VEX在此分道扬镳，没想到如今的久别重逢。与熟悉的金属结构件相遇、与机器人对抗电机高速旋转的齿轮声相遇，更重要的，更重要的是与初中时有着共同热爱与梦想的同学们和老师重逢。这一切都让我激动不已，就像是星星之火在无数个暴风雪夜之后重新成为熊熊烈火一样，照亮了我的心。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当然，新的问题接踵而至。VEX推出了全新的V5主控套装，新的编程环境，这一切都是需要我去学习和尽快掌握新的知识；这里有了更多陌生的面孔，有身经百战的学姐和学长、还有已经征战将近一个赛季的国一的同学们。而我，作为一个新加入机器人社团大家庭的人，如何让大家认识我、了解我、信任我是亟待解决的问题。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May be the FIRST DAY?</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-04-22-may-be-the-first-day.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-04-22-may-be-the-first-day.md/</guid>
      <description>It’s 2:51 now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIT REFRESH</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-03-10-hit-refresh.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-03-10-hit-refresh.md/</guid>
      <description>It’s my first blog in English.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
