<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Haojin&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Haojin&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>@2018-2023 Haojin Li</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 23:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Physical Exercises</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-08-30-physical-exercises.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-08-30-physical-exercises.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 28th, I went to a military training base in rural area of my city with my fellow students. Originally, I thought it would be a tough time based on all my past formidable experience with such training. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take it anymore during my time in both middle and high school. I took a trip and had computer science classes instead. A fun fact is that I became the whitest among my class after they coming back from training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from worry, excitement also haunted around me because it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time to have a training. The result turned out it didn&amp;rsquo;t let me down and I really learned a lot from this fantastic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-team-leader&#34; class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Being a team leader &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying my best to be the team leader is always my style, especially participating in a short-time camp. I frimly deem it&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity to promote and improve myself. Then I became the leader of group 6 without any hesitate. I deeply know that I am lack of leadership and most important, the decisive personality. This time I failed again on improving that. Everytime I become a leader in a program, unfortunately, I never felt improvement in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I believe I did great a great job. Organizing the team, encourging everyone doing high-altitude program and cimmitting myself to everything I can.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech at Foundation Class</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-07-16-speech-at-foundation-class.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-07-16-speech-at-foundation-class.md/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Final Exam</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-06-29-chinese-final-exam.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-06-29-chinese-final-exam.md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;局促的咨询室里，有升学指导老师、母亲和他，还有从始至终都没有动过的三杯水。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“老师好，我叫李昊锦，在西安高新第一中学国际班就读，我喜欢计算机，我是……”，他像是背顺口溜一样，一个绊子都没有，非常流利地在母亲和老师面前做了自我介绍。与其说是他在说话，不如说他的嘴巴在发声。这一番话他不知讲了多少遍，在多少个局促的教室里，对着多少初次见面的老师，当然还有每次都陪着的他的母亲，不，他陪着的母亲。他明白自己不能惹母亲生气，每一次都极不情愿地答应与母亲去各种中介办公室交流谈话，而母亲每次都会说这是最后一次，以后他都不用去了。像极了小时候父母哄孩子喝苦涩的中药，但最终都是为了孩子好。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIX RHWSS Project Presentation Videos</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-02-16-gix-rhwss-project-presentation-videos.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 15:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-02-16-gix-rhwss-project-presentation-videos.md/</guid>
      <description>{% youtube wh_07GoQKvk %}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>西雅图 Day4</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-02-12-%E8%A5%BF%E9%9B%85%E5%9B%BE-day4.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-02-12-%E8%A5%BF%E9%9B%85%E5%9B%BE-day4.md/</guid>
      <description>Introduction of Text Entry 人机交互 人与信息系统的信息交换过程</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
